I have big news.
A couple news.
First things first.
We're starting over.
I don't even want to think about the last dream.
That was a pure fever dream and I regret everything.
I just want to leave that behind me.
We're going to go in fresh.
Because I was going to migrate anyway.
I was going to move away anyway, but you know what?
That world now has bad thoughts embedded in it.
So I'm going to start fresh and we're going to do this properly.
No deaths.
Beautiful progression.
Amazing inventory management.
No getting crazy messed up in the head looking at the inventory not knowing what to do with it.
This time we do it right from the start.
The second news.
You guys told me to mod my game.
So I fucking modded my game.
Literally, I made my own mod.
I did not add anything other than create.
It's still just create and aeronautics.
And of course we have the gym button.
I got rid of JEI because it's ugly.
I made my own native implementation.
Of create.
Embedded in the vanilla interface.
So much so that a common person would think that Mojang themselves did it.
It's going to be good.
Crossing fingers, no bugs.
You know what went wrong last time?
Like it all spiraled out of control.
First thing, I was also drinking.
So that didn't help.
Today we're not drinking.
Clear headed.
Clear goals.
Raise a sharp focus.
And there was a lot of viewers last time.
And there still is now.
And I'm not going to lie to you.
That made me a little nervous.
I'm not used to having this many viewers looking.
And judging my gameplay.
So that definitely made it worse for me.
Like I definitely, you know, I was stumbling around.
Freaking fumbling in the dark.
Not knowing what to do.
Being overwhelmed with all the new items and shit.
Today is going to be different.
Performance anxiety.
Exactly.
Something like that.
I did not add farmer's delight.
I did take a look at it.
But you know what?
There's already so much in this mod, guys.
I'm going to keep it simple.
This is a create playthrough.
Just create with aeronautics.
We'll have a lot of fun though.
Maybe in the far future, we're going to do a crazy one where we just pour in everything.
For now though, we're sticking to create.
But, I do have the gym button.
So we got to make a button today at some point.
It's not a Minecraft stream without the gym button, right?
I can't believe there's 900 people watching.
You guys are addicted to Minecraft, dude.
Where's everybody when I'm streaming Sims?
Huh?
That game is great as well, guys.
If you haven't played Sims.
Cheers.
No, not Sims.
The Sims.
From 1990-something.
Oh, that was a beautiful transition.
I nailed that one.
Oh.
I will show you my mods.
People were requesting it last time.
I don't know what these are.
I didn't install these.
I'm assuming they're dependency packs.
I don't know why there's two of these.
I swear I only did install that once.
But who knows.
And that's it.
That is it.
Okay.
That being said.
Let's get into it.
We are going to delete this world.
The contemporary world was a bad world.
Boom!
We're gonna have a new world.
It is going to be...
A new dawn.
This is peak gameplay today.
Survival.
We're gonna put it on hard.
And that's it.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Just kidding.
Come on.
We're in the jungle.
Or something.
Let's give it a moment just to load everything in.
Oh my goodness.
We've got frogs as well.
Wait.
This is not a jungle.
This is like a swamp.
Wait.
What just happened there?
Okay.
It's still lagging.
I'm just gonna...
Let it load in the terrain.
I can just hear my CPU spinning up.
Hey look.
A tiny penis.
I remember seeing those ones.
Wait.
I can't grab them.
Okay.
I don't know.
Ooh.
It's lagging here.
Please finish loading.
Come on.
What was that jump?
Yeah.
This is not a good spot.
I don't like this spawn.
This is horrible.
We're moving on to greener pastures.
I need green areas.
Farmland.
Because this time I really am gonna farm.
And we're gonna grab animals.
We're gonna do everything right.
But first we get some wood.
This is like the iconic Minecraft start, you know?
Hitting a tree.
Brings me nostalgia already.
Not the same type of nostalgia that you guys have for like, you know, 15 years ago or something.
Just a couple years for me, but still, I have it.
Make them all into that.
Gonna make one of these.
And I guess we could make a boat real quick.
No, no, no.
Start by making, uh, simple tools.
Like 24.
There we go.
I'm also gonna make an axe.
Come with me.
Okay.
Okay, so.
Which way is the green?
I see green over there.
Let's go.
Also, I'm purposefully not running because I don't have any food right now.
Notice the improved gameplay already.
Right off the bat.
We're not gonna be out of stamina and not being able to run from enemies when they appear.
We're gonna kill these pigs immediately because that's food.
Such efficiency.
And I will calm down today and fix my inventory as we go along.
Otherwise, it, you know, it adds up and it breaks my brain.
I forgot what these drop.
Nothing.
Okay.
I'm gonna run a little bit now that I have food.
Maybe I'll take a little bit more wood now that I have an axe.
Dude, I am actually...
I wasn't sure last time I told you this about, you know, creating all that.
But after playing it last time, I'm sold now.
You know, that's why I also want to start over.
I want to do this right.
I want to freaking...
Oh, I'm actually so excited.
There's so much stuff we're gonna explore and find.
Hell yeah.
Let's keep some of these.
Just in case we need them.
Okay, next up, we need to find stone.
Oh, this is a beautiful area.
I can see myself settling down here.
Definitely.
But I see stone over there.
So I'm going.
15 steaks as well.
Or pork chops.
Now we just need some fuel.
A.K.A.
Whatchamacallit.
The black stuff you can burn.
Coal.
Oh, sheep!
This is a bed right here.
Three sheeps.
That's the beds.
There we go.
Look at me.
What a start!
This is the start.
Three white wool.
That's a bed right there.
Another one.
And another one.
There's actually more sheep over there.
Guys, we need sheep for windmill sails.
I will kill the cows.
But I have to hurry, kind of.
Okay, still midday.
I mean, we have a bed now, so we can actually totally chill.
And there's no going in caves until we have armor.
We're not going to fail like last time.
Wonderful.
Lots of sticks.
Oops.
I don't think I've missed a single hit yet on an animal.
With the jump attack.
Saving durability on my axe as well.
You know?
Ah!
We gotta get out of here.
It's not that bad.
This is definitely a minor crime.
I will get these.
I'm not going to settle here anyway, so, you know.
I'm shitting where I don't eat.
Let's go get some stone.
Man, look at this right here.
Am I ready or what?
For survival.
I think I'm ready.
That's enough of me to sustain a whole family for at least a week.
We also need stone for a furnace.
But let's be efficient here and immediately create a stone axe.
So we can mine even faster.
And watch this.
This is the new me.
Fuck that.
We don't need it.
Let's not have it clutter the inventory.
I'm also gonna make a shovel.
I'm not even using the book.
Notice how proficient I am.
Oh, good start here.
This has to be the most ideal start that I've ever had in Minecraft.
We got sheep.
We got meat.
We got everything.
Coal.
Doesn't get better than this.
Oh, it does get better.
There's iron.
Oh, what a start.
Yeah, this is definitely the best of all time.
I'm gonna...
How do I get up there?
Actually, I'm gonna make a little path in the mountain.
Just like the dwarves.
This is how I'm getting up there.
And I'm getting coal...
I mean, stone at the same time.
And the day's not even over yet.
Wait, did I just...
Okay, never mind.
I thought I just got a block of iron.
It was just a normal iron.
That reminds me, we also got to create a block of iron.
That was essential last time.
To get some...
Something.
I forgot what it was.
Some kind of machine that was useful.
Copper here, too.
I'm gonna make a thingy now.
Let's start cooking.
Let's cook some food first.
Maybe we do steaks.
Because it heals even more.
I'm gonna grab this.
We probably don't need...
That much copper.
To begin with here.
Yeah, this will do.
Ooh.
Money.
Wow.
Ah, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Am I destroying that?
I think I can't use a stone on that.
I need to find a iron pickaxe.
Okay, that's good enough for now.
Put the iron in there.
Very good.
While that's cooking, let's go find some more stuff.
Maybe some more iron.
There's coal up there.
I actually take that.
And let's also make some torches immediately.
Ah, I don't have any coal yet.
This is already so much better.
I'm, like, calming down, you know?
We don't need that much copper.
Actually, I guess we can have one stack of copper.
And then no more.
It's just for inventory space issues reasons.
There we go.
That's good.
I saw cows down there.
Let's kill them.
More steaks.
And leather.
I gotta get ready for night soon.
So we gotta make a bet.
Let's make that immediately.
Eat the steak.
It's still cooking.
So we're gonna have an iron pickaxe now.
Here we go.
Boom.
And, new me.
Fuck that thing.
Look how clean this inventory is, man!
So good.
Bed.
I'm ready to sleep.
Yeah!
Oh, what a first day!
This has to be, like, a record.
Holy shit.
And now we're gonna make more iron?
No.
Food.
And while that's cooking, let's, uh...
Go up here.
Now that we have this pickaxe, we can grab this.
Yeah!
Sweet.
What else do we need?
We need andesite!
Let's find some andesite, and...
We also need zinc.
I think zinc may be underground, so...
Let's wait a bit until we have a little bit of armor before we go down.
This is a new rule.
We never go caving without armor!
Then again, you gotta go caving a little bit just to get enough iron for that.
Also getting good experience here.
Nice.
Oh, that also gives experience, just cooking food.
I thought it was just minerals and stuff.
Or metals.
Put that there.
Okay, while that is cooking, let's, uh...
Look for some andesite?
Maybe down here.
That actually looks like a cave situation.
Tell me it's a big cave.
Oh.
Boo.
What?
There's a little hole up there.
Maybe that leads to something?
Back there.
I see something back there.
Oh, I should make a blast furnace.
Or a blast smoke, or whatever it was called.
What was that?
That was a weird sound.
Oh, maybe?
Maybe?
Oh.
We got something.
But I got no torches, so we don't go down.
New Dawn, new me.
I'm a changed man.
Don't take stupid risks.
I will kill you.
I need to make sails out of your skin.
Taking you as well.
Man, so many animals here, though.
There's a cow up there.
Oh!
That could potentially lead to something.
But I like the cave I saw over there.
That's going to be the new destination.
Let's find the furnace here.
Also, the lags have stopped, so the world is generated now.
Feels good, yo.
Yeah.
Take this.
And we're going to make some torches.
Boom.
48 is good.
But I want more.
Oh, wait.
Here.
And here.
64.
One stack.
For inventory space reasons.
And...
Are we good?
We have wood.
We brought that with us.
We will never go into a cave without wood again.
Beefs are being cooked.
Or they are cooked.
Let's go.
Oh!
I need to make a shield!
That's the big thing.
Shield, shield, shield.
Oh, nice!
And then we have the axe.
Lovely.
I could even make, like, a better shovel if I wanted to, but no.
Honestly, the stone axe is a...
really decent combat weapon.
You almost don't need anything else in this game.
Give me a shield and a stone axe.
I mean...
Yeah, a stone axe, and I can do anything.
Now we have torches, and we also brought the bed, and we have the furnace with us.
Good.
We're gonna keep torches on the right side?
Oh!
Oh, wait.
That's not even a cave.
Oh.
Well, you know what?
Efficiency me.
I take the torch with me.
Nothing goes to waste here.
Let's go back out.
We're moving on to greener pastures.
We also go, uh...
sail somewhere.
What was that just now?
Oh!
A village!
Let's go rob them.
Get a jumpstart.
On our tech tree.
Although, I really want a proper cave.
Maybe they have leather armor, actually.
That could help.
Let me see.
Oh, is that...
That's a smoker.
I'm taking that.
Yoink!
That's mine now.
Wait, what?
What just happened here?
Water's going crazy.
Let me do...
Let me fix that.
I did already rob them, so let me help them out in turn.
There you go.
What's going on here?
You got bookcases for me.
One of those.
These ones I cannot destroy, right?
I mean, I can, but...
Yeah, they're gonna be turned into books.
Actually, that's fine.
I'll take some books.
Thank you very much, sir.
You'll survive without these books.
Trust me.
You'll be fine.
We also have these for food, but I don't really want those.
I have steaks.
What's with the water situation in this village?
You guys have flooding issues.
Huh?
Let me fix that.
There you go.
Mm-hmm.
Let me check this one.
There we go!
And money!
I'm stealing their money.
Armor!
Yeah, that's right.
You saw me take that.
I need it, okay?
I'm an adventurer.
I'm going out into the wild.
Maybe I don't want any of this.
Yeah.
Stick to the inventory clean.
We're not gonna mess it up.
No thanks.
Actually, maybe I'll bring some seeds.
Just to get a farm started, right?
All right.
Pretty cool village.
There we go.
Acacia sapling.
Don't care.
Hey, you know what?
I want this bed.
You can have this bed.
I want orange bed.
All right.
Let's go find a cave, huh?
It's cave time.
Maybe here?
Nah.
If there's water, it's always bad.
Where do I go?
Maybe I'll make a boat, actually.
An oak boat.
A boke.
Oh, yeah.
Let's find the perfect spot.
We're gonna look for...
Oh, we can also take this.
Ah, but then our inventory is at stake.
Keeping it clean is a priority, right?
Ah, fuck it.
Not right now.
I'll worry about that later.
Keep it simple.
Raise your sharp focus.
These trees are funny looking.
I think I want to go to that mountain.
There's also some kind of...
Is that a marshland over there?
Or is that a...
No, that's a marshland.
It's not a jungle.
Oh, look at that.
That's a cave right there.
And that's gonna lead me down to riches.
Could also kill some more sheep.
Get some wool.
Actually, I'm gonna do it.
We gotta make sails to make a windmill.
So we can grind our wheat.
Man, I'm a menace to sheep society.
I have killed, like, 20.
In the span of...
Well, 10 minutes or so.
Where's this cave at?
Trust, this will be a good one.
Never mind.
Or...
No.
False alarm.
Dang.
But you know what?
Maybe the game not throwing me an amazing cave to start off with is actually a blessing in disguise.
Because otherwise I would be...
you know, lured in there from the get-go and lose everything.
Not this time.
I kill only white sheep.
Because the colors don't match in the recipes.
So everyone who's not white...
gets to live!
That sounds fucked up when you say it like that.
Okay, let's go to bed.
Cheers.
Oh yeah.
Come on, game.
Bless me with a cave.
Dude, what even is this area?
That's like a huge marshland right there.
Don't follow the lights.
Thank you.
I'm gonna kill this sheep as well.
Dude, when I finally do find zinc...
I will have so much stuff to accelerate like crazy.
The tech tree, I mean.
Oh, I also have a smoker now, so I can really easily cook my food.
When I find a good spot to settle.
That's a jungle over there.
That's a big jungle too.
I don't want to be in a jungle.
Although I've never tried it, it could be kind of cool to make some kind of...
jungle house out of bamboo and jungle wood.
Like Mowgli.
Didn't he create one of those houses?
In one of those stories?
I think he did.
It was crafty.
You know what?
I hope future Minecraft versions include a thing where you can just boat across here.
Or like, very slowly, you don't get up on land and then...
instead of having to get off the boat.
Because that is infuriating.
You could just mod that, I guess.
The world is my oyster now.
I can do anything.
Oh, I gotta get the diving helmet and stuff so then we can grab all this stuff down here.
Imagine, this is like a cave!
That right there is a massive, amazing cave that we could explore if we had the back tank and all that.
A birch forest.
Okay, but where are the caves?
Oh, more sheep.
There we go.
I'm purposefully going slow here.
To get the basic needs taken care of before I go too crazy with the advanced stuff.
Okay, that's good.
I hear a dog!
Do I have any bones?
No!
Oh, that's too bad.
I haven't even seen a single enemy in this game yet.
What the hell?
Did I accidentally put it on easy or something?
Oh, oh, oh!
Here we go!
Oh!
There we go!
Let's do this!
Let's dance!
There we go!
Not today, my friend.
Not today.
Oh, that's a nice cave right there.
But let's go this way first.
Is this a dead end?
Because if it is...
then good!
Don't have to worry about that.
We're also going to put down a bed here.
Just in case.
Playing it safe.
Let's put it here.
Respawn point set.
And then we explore.
Torch is on the right.
Oh!
There we go!
Oh, look at this!
I also see andesite.
It's happening.
Let me grab that.
Yeah.
Andesite is what we need.
I'm not going to do anything with it yet.
I'm just going to take it and decide what to do with it later.
Would love to get a little bit of diamond as well.
Just to get a pickaxe.
That is almost a necessity, you know?
Just having the diamond pickaxe.
What's that?
Oh, it's gravel.
Wait a minute.
Gravel is actually just the same texture as andesite, but colored differently, if you think about it.
Isn't that kind of crazy?
I think I'll take two stacks of this.
Good start.
I'm going to take some from here.
It's so calm and peaceful in this cave.
Oh, we should also get an enchantment table kind of early.
You know?
So we can actually become powerful.
And not suck so much.
Now we just need to find zinc.
Oh, you know what?
I should have let my smoker done something while I did this.
Oh, no.
Efficiency is at an all-time low now.
Okay, we have two stacks of this.
Next time I start mining, I'm going to do that.
Oh, I'm also going to stick to the schedule here.
And not do that.
Keep those on the right.
Oh, lava.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
That's kind of dangerous.
You want to come here?
Come on, then.
No?
What's going on, friend?
Oh, feisty are you?
And you're dead.
We need to make a path up.
Check my six.
Okay.
I'm making a safety two-by-two staircase in case I need to run later.
There's no way I fucked this up now.
Oh, we got specialized textures.
This is that green stuff.
Oh, iron.
Zinc!
Finally, we can wash our hands!
Great!
Scott!
I don't know why, but this place is giving me the pooping feeling right now.
I may actually have to go take care of that soon.
Okay, that was a short enjoyment.
Can we get more zinc?
It's too quiet in here!
Why is it so quiet?
You may think, Oliver, you have so much coal.
Stop!
And I say, No.
You can't have too much coal.
Oh!
Oh, something new.
It's just...
Tripstone.
More zinc.
What about diamonds, though?
Y'all got any of that?
Uh-oh!
We have a...
Dude.
Oy, oy, oy!
Okay.
Can you get up here?
Let me make it easy for you.
Oh, he's waiting for me.
Come on, then!
Oh, you still can't reach me?
Oh!
It's just water.
Fuckin' hell.
Oh, this is actually getting a little...
Questionable!
Oh, shit.
I gotta heal.
Playing it safe.
Dude, you can really feel not having armor.
It's crazy.
Sup, man?
Oh, that's too bad.
Good.
Don't want to jump down there.
There's dripstones and they hurt.
Slow descent.
Oh, yeah.
We got bones now for bone mule.
That's great for the farming.
Very good.
Also got some redstone.
Ooh, diamonds soon?
Slow and methodical.
I have so many recipes unlocked right now.
I saw a skeleton, by the way.
No, zombie.
Yo!
Okay, this is definitely diamond central.
I can tell you that.
I also see iron up there.
But how am I gonna traverse this?
Ooh.
Wait a minute.
I actually have so much iron right now.
I really should be making iron armor right now.
Let's not be dumb.
Furnace.
Half.
Smoker.
Smoke my meat.
And make the iron.
Oh, yeah.
What does it take to make the battle smoker thingy?
No.
What am I saying?
The blast furnace.
Blast furnace.
Oh, I don't have it yet.
Oh, shit.
I don't remember what it takes to get that.
So now...
Oh!
Good thing I just stopped here, huh?
There we go.
Make a new one.
Maybe I should replace my axe as well.
Yeah, let's do it.
No more stone.
What do I not need?
I do need the rest.
Maybe not diorite.
Nobody cares about that.
Oh, I should make a little, uh...
I was about to say chest, but, uh...
Probably not a good idea.
Okay, so I already have a chest piece.
We can make boots.
No, let's make legs.
That's more worth.
And legs cost what?
Seven.
How many do I have?
Okay, I need one more.
Ah, it's looking good!
It's looking good!
So more iron would be nice.
There we go.
Suit up.
Ready for combat.
I'm gonna leave this here, actually.
Dankeschön.
We also need to get across.
Oh, there's iron up there.
I'm gonna take that.
Dude, I'm impressed with myself so far.
This is going splendidly.
Nothing like last time.
No?
Anything else I need before I go?
Oh, yeah, shovel.
Shovel.
So I actually do need this.
Oh, wait!
Uh.
I need an axe.
Good thing I just got some more iron.
Yeah, we need to make an axe, and then we go.
Axe, and then we go, and then what else?
Well, I could make this.
May as well do it.
Yeah.
Better than nothing.
Yes, sir!
Look at me using every part of the animal.
Axe, I need one more for that.
That.
And torches, 47.
We can...
make a couple more.
Give me that one.
Let's get up to, like...
55.
64.
Beautiful.
That is lovely.
We don't care about this dripstone at all, so we're going to throw that away.
Bone we keep.
Arrows.
Honestly?
No.
I'll get that later.
For now, it's not yet bow-tech time.
That was hard to say.
It's not yet bow-tech time.
English is hard.
Okay.
Here we go.
I'm crossing the gap.
Ooh.
Think.
That is very far down.
I really gotta be careful here.
I'm so scared.
If there's a bowman somewhere, I'm in trouble.
Yeah, you can't reach me.
Did that guy just fell down?
What an idiot.
Please don't hit me with the karma now.
Right after saying that.
I beg you.
Hey!
You wanna get up here?
Come on.
Are you stuck on that dripstone?
What's happening?
Hello?
Oh, that's too bad.
No diamonds in sight.
How much redstone do I have?
I can take a bit more.
Oh.
Oh yeah, it became dark.
Check my six.
Time it.
I think I missed that one.
Ah, it's okay.
Hey!
Thank you!
He revealed diamonds!
That is insane!
Wow!
I wouldn't have found this!
If he hadn't exploded.
He also got gold.
Oh yeah, dude.
What a start!
Hadn't died yet, by the way.
Just wanna point that out.
This is truly a new dawn!
You feel it?
Oops.
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
We got 50 redstone dust.
We can take a bit more.
I don't want more than one stack, though.
That's good.
64.
And then we throw this away.
Bop!
Like that.
What's this song?
I don't recognize this song.
New song?
I actually wonder if they are new songs.
It's fine, it's fine.
Man, I didn't see you there.
You were freaking blending in with the environment.
Wow.
Oof.
Actually, I'm so worried about a creeper just coming up behind me and killing me.
That could be a way to die.
You know, if I don't pay attention like this, I just look behind me.
My head needs to be on a swivel.
Oh.
It's just a bat.
Oh man, my arm on edge right now.
Uh, wait.
I have to remember to go back as well.
So we can't get too lost in here.
Remember where we are.
We have a trail of torches.
Everything's fine.
Got more zinc as well.
What a day.
What a feeling.
Minecraft is a feeling.
Um, yeah, put it here.
I'm already so ready for, uh, making the alloy and getting started with all that.
But I'm gonna use the time that I have in here to the maximum, you know?
I found a great cave.
I'm not gonna waste it.
Great caves come to those who wait.
And I definitely did wait.
Show me diamonds.
That's what I really want right now.
We don't want this.
Diamonds!
Very good.
I'm making a little path for myself if I have to suddenly run.
I'm surprised at the lack of, uh, monsters in here.
Like, where are they?
Usually in a dark place like this, it would be crawling with monsters, but...
There's one.
Check behind me.
I think I already have enough for full iron armor.
Oh, I should eat.
Keep that up.
Maybe I have too much zinc.
Nah.
No way.
Also, how's my inventory doing?
Doing okay.
We can throw away this bow for sure, though.
And this.
And that's about it.
Ah!
No!
That fucking came out of nowhere!
That wasn't even someone behind me!
First one doesn't count!
I can't believe it!
Why'd it have to end like that?
Oh, man.
You can't peek too much in this game.
The game will know.
And they're gonna put you in your spot.
Fuck.
Good thing I made a nice path for myself and lit up the path, huh?
This is why I set up all these safety measures here.
Christ.
Dude, that scared the shit out of me!
I thought I had my six checked!
He must have spawned behind me or some bullshit like that.
I'm gonna frickin' murder this guy with a dripstone.
Stab him in the eye with it.
And kill him until he dies from it.
He down there?
No, he exploded.
Okay, grab it quick!
Jesus Christ.
Gimme.
That's it.
Okay, back to the light.
Oh, my God.
Lost my experience, but it's fine.
It's okay.
Check your six.
Where are my boots?
Maybe then my boots exploded.
I don't know what's happened.
Fortress on five.
Yeah, you know what?
I'm not done exploring here.
I keep moving on.
Just light this up in case someone spawns there.
Maybe he spawned up here and fell down on me or something.
Oh, what?
Give me that.
And throw the things away we don't want.
That seems about right.
Oh, there are my boots.
Good.
All right, we're back.
Man, that was...
That was quite a rude awakening there.
You know what?
It's okay.
It's like...
I need to be humbled, you know?
Otherwise, I will become too powerful.
I was definitely peeking too much.
I need to be kept in check here.
There we go, baby.
And there's even one more.
Oh.
Fantastic.
Stay humble.
No more getting overconfident.
It is a...
Killer.
An insidious one.
Stay safe.
All right, I'm gonna get up there.
Did I leave behind my cobblestone?
That was a mistake.
Oh, my shovel.
Oh, that's not...
Wait, wait, what?
Scoria?
Dude, this looks like dirt.
The hell is this?
That's new.
Scoria.
All right.
I wonder what I can do with that.
What's this?
That's tough.
I don't trust any of these textures anymore.
I'll take this as well.
Getting ready for enchanting.
Yeah.
Oh, let's not forget, we're gonna turn everything into blocks.
That's the space saver.
I used to do that a lot.
In the past.
I'm still recovering from that explosion.
That was truly one of the biggest jump scares from a creeper that I've ever gotten.
It truly came out of nowhere.
I'm scared!
I don't wanna...
Please don't fall behind me.
Don't kill me, please.
I need to drink.
I need to stay hydrated.
Make a...
Yeah, staircase.
I am getting a little far away from my...
Outpost.
I see you back there.
Looks like this is the end of the line.
That's honestly fine with me.
I got what I came for!
Yikes.
Oh, okay.
We're doing this.
Wait, what is this place even?
Why is there water in there?
I actually wanna take a look.
Just a quick peek.
Oh, okay.
Does not look pleasant.
I thought maybe there was a place we could breathe, but no.
Oh, you can't...
Cross?
That's too bad.
Oh, wait.
Maybe he...
Came from up there and then went that way.
I also see more iron.
You know what?
I'm gonna go up here.
I'm gonna use Scoria to get up there.
Oh, shit.
Where?
Oh, there you are.
Fucking hell.
Fine.
Come to me.
Yeah.
Suck!
Eat.
Back up.
I will not be bullied by these people.
Get up there fast.
I'm happy with that.
Iron fell down.
Uh-oh.
How do you know I'm here?
Good night.
I cannot get lost.
I am still fully aware of where I am.
Okay.
I think I got what I came for.
I'm going back.
I am happy.
Don't push the lemon!
Ooh!
That could have been really bad.
But we're good, though.
Came out on top, after all.
Okay, how about we go find a peaceful place out on the prairie and settle down for a bit, huh?
Get some cows going and some wheat.
And just soak in the sun.
I deserve it.
After this ordeal.
Inventory is still pristine looking.
Absolutely pristine.
I don't even want gunpowder.
That's right.
I don't want it.
I reject.
I reject the gunpowder so I can have a clean inventory.
Later, we focus on gunpowder.
Same way back.
Don't overcomplicate it.
Who knows?
Maybe I'll come back to this specific cave later.
Nah.
Probably not.
But I could.
Wait, how did I get here?
Oh, wait.
It was over here.
Right here.
I think.
Yeah.
There it is.
Now we have torches on the left.
Oh, it's beautiful.
What a caving expedition.
I mean, we died, but...
First doesn't count.
Oh.
Let's get the bet.
Can't forget that.
Let's go.
That was beautiful.
That was absolute perfection.
Okay, so the question is...
Oh, let's go to bed.
Four monsters come.
Okay.
I feel like, man...
That creeper death was...
How do you even avoid that?
You know?
It's literally just...
Oh, you're alive.
Now you're dead.
And you didn't even see anything coming.
So maybe I should start classifying those deaths as not counting, just in general.
Which means I still have...
The first doesn't count.
No.
No, no, no.
Now we'll have armor, so I will never die to them again.
Oh!
You saw that?
Pretty good.
Okay.
Let's go...
I was about to say this way, but we can't.
I need big open spaces.
With no crimes.
Preferably.
But if I have to survive crimes, fine.
I'll do it.
I will endure.
So I came from here, but...
I want to keep going in this direction.
Bup, bup.
Beating the fishes.
Oh!
One thing I need to find, though, is...
I'm trying to remember the name now.
It's not Prismarine.
It is...
The freaking Shards.
You know?
The ones that make Spyglass.
Those are the ones I need to find.
Too bad I didn't find them in that cave.
Let's go here.
Honestly, this place is pretty good looking.
Maybe in, like, a little mini forest like this could be kind of nice.
Having a hut.
I'm imagining some kind of structure where...
When you walk through the forest, you kind of see the outline of it.
Because there's multiple...
Levels to it, you know?
Like a tower, maybe.
Like a castle.
But a...
Contemporary...
Not contemporary, but like...
Not medieval either.
You know?
Somewhere in between.
I'm thinking of a French castle.
An old French castle.
But a little more modern than that.
You get what I'm trying to say, right?
Follow the river.
And then we make a windmill.
And we get started on everything.
Oh, I gotta make my, uh...
My spinny destroyer.
Fuck, what is it called?
Saw.
So I can chop down some trees.
I think that should be the way we do it.
So...
We find a good spot.
Where we make a home.
We create the saw.
With the hand crank.
And we're gonna crank that shit!
And basically eradicate an entire forest.
And then we come back with, like, a million wood.
And we really get to building.
Can't wait to do that, actually.
And obviously we're gonna make a fucking car at some point.
I am so curious about that still.
I have a feeling, though, it's quite far in the future in terms of progression.
But we'll see.
Maybe it's closer than I think.
Ah!
There you go.
Good enough.
This is a nice place.
Maybe up there?
Where I can look across the land?
Oh!
Wait a sec.
That looks pretty cool.
Wait, is there something up there?
That looks like a house up there!
Or is that just weirdly rectangular...
No, that is not a house.
Damn, I thought that was a house up there.
Imagine.
That would be the coolest village of all time.
Let's go up there and have a look around.
Sad, with no spyglass, but you know.
We'll have to make do.
And from up there, we're gonna find the perfect spot.
If that isn't the perfect spot already.
The thing is, though, getting back up there every time seems like a chore.
But then again!
Apparently you can make an elevator or some shit, right?
Hmm.
Oh, whoa!
Village!
Wait.
A tale of two cities?
I'm gonna be up there?
They're gonna be over there?
I like it!
Dude, this is it.
And a windmill up there is even better!
Imagine that.
Are you imagining it?
Now amplify that feeling by ten.
That's how I'm feeling.
It's a good feeling.
Can't wait to see the view up here.
Oh, wait, no.
It's...
Multiple peaks.
Oh, but it is nice, isn't it?
Let me see this peak, then.
Just to compare.
Maybe I like this peak more.
Oh, there's like a little hole through the mountain there?
That looks nice.
Yeah?
I can see this being pretty good.
I'm taking this.
I mean, when they just present me with iron like that, I gotta take it.
Is that a cow or something?
Oh, my goodness.
I don't like the...
The hole of death in the middle of everything.
It's not very suitable for a home.
But it would be nice to have some sort of access to a cave.
But imagine, though, we make here, and we make a bridge to over there or something.
Oh, that's not gonna work, is it?
This is a nice spot, though.
Oh, look at this down there!
That could be good.
But guys, I actually gotta go.
I gotta take a quick break here.
I need to go to the toilet.
I'm sorry.
I'll see you in a bit.
All
right.
Let's go.
What was I doing?
Oh, yeah.
I was thinking of where to put down my base.
So I was thinking of putting it on that peak, but I think I'm gonna hate going up and down that peak all the time.
So, maybe that's for later or something, you know?
Oh, watch this.
Yeah!
I know Minecraft tricks!
That's right.
That's how you get down a mountain fast, kids.
Kind of weird how that works.
Like, why are you able to do that?
Right?
Now, there is also a...
legitimate idea here, where you go to the nether fast.
No, you go to...
Oh, wait.
Never mind.
I was about to say you go to the end to get the elytra, but you don't really easily go to the end.
Because you need, like, Eyes of Ender and shit.
That's...
No, that takes a while.
Because I was gonna say, let's get the elytra and then look for a base.
But that's easier said than done.
For sure.
I didn't think.
That's a...
What the...
My screen is, like, blacking out sometimes.
Weird.
I think it's when it's loading, because I'm moving through new territory here.
Ah, this is a nice spot, actually.
Near the river?
But I'm not satisfied yet.
We need to find a perfect spot, right?
No matter what.
There was a village back there.
I could have explored.
Oh, mountains.
Actually, I'm gonna kill more sheep.
Getting so much wool.
Oh, what do I mean to jump like that?
Would be kind of nice to live in the snow biome.
I've never done that.
You know?
Make a fire.
Make a cup of tea.
And sit there.
And enjoy it all.
That'd be kind of cool.
I think jungle is probably my least...
Uh...
Favorite place to make a base.
Even though I haven't tried it.
It's just...
It's a little too dense for me, you know?
I can't really see.
And I need to be able to see.
Doesn't that look like an angel in disguise?
Just sort of...
Looking ominously at me right there, with his arms stretched out?
Like the come at me bro meme.
The ultimate crime.
Oh, or this place.
Mushroom place with the big fat trees.
Okay, I think I'm gonna do that actually.
Let's make a house in the forest.
Harder to find later when I get lost, but...
I think it's gonna be nice.
Now to find the perfect spot in the forest.
Oh, sun's going down.
That means sleep.
Straight from the boat into the bed.
And then we can get high on mushrooms too.
Mmm.
Not bad.
Get off here.
I mean, it is kind of dense, isn't it?
This is very close to the starting area...
of the world I had in the second season.
Minus the mushrooms.
We had like mossy rocks and stuff.
Which was actually such a nice place.
But like, if I make a base right here, how am I ever gonna find it again?
It's too dense.
Even while I'm in here, I can't really see through the treetops.
It's questionable.
Let's see what's over here.
Mountain range in the distance.
Actually looks really cool.
Lava?
Oh, wait.
I can make obsidian here.
I just need a bucket.
Ah, but I don't have a diamond pickaxe yet.
But I could make one.
Should I?
Not yet.
We'll find more lava.
And I don't have any use for obsidian right now anyway.
I could go to the nether, but I don't want to yet.
We need to be fully prepared for that.
With a bow, at least.
What the hell is going on?
I don't know if you guys have seen this at all.
Or maybe it's just me.
Well, if I see it, you guys should see it.
Like my game is crapping itself.
This is kind of nice.
This is a better forest.
It's not too thick.
Depending on what's on the other side here, this may be the place.
You see access to a cave.
Ooh.
And there's a beach as well.
Oh, okay.
I think we found it.
Yeah, this is it.
This is the spot.
I love it.
Let's make it right here.
Yo, check it out.
What if we make the house right above this gulch or whatever?
And then we have like an axis hatched down into whatever that is down there.
That sounds cool, doesn't it?
And then the house goes right here.
With a roof on it and everything.
Oh.
That sounds really cool.
I'm doing that.
Yes.
First things first, though.
Let's set up a little preliminary base.
That was hard to say.
So we plop down all these essentials.
We have like a little working area.
The working area will be over here.
Smoker.
And furnace.
And a bed.
That's the working area.
Respawn set.
We're also gonna make a...
Oh.
Gonna make a little perimeter here.
With some light.
For when night comes.
Am I a changed man or what?
Holy shit.
It's like we're cordoning off the area for construction.
Dude, I love that, actually.
Nice.
Obviously, we need more light inside the center, too.
But we're gonna get there.
Where's my first torch?
Somewhere over here.
Wait, where did I put the torch?
Ah, there it is.
Okay, and now we do the center part here, like this.
Oh, we already had one there.
Maybe one there.
We need one right here as well, of course.
Here.
Obviously, this is easier to do at night, where you can see the light radius.
But this will do.
This is gonna be so dope.
Let me put one more over here.
All these torches are also temporary, of course.
We're gonna have beautiful lighting later.
Alright.
Let's make a chest.
In fact, we're gonna make two chests.
And we're gonna do a little bit of preliminary sorting already.
Okay?
So, this tree right here represents our working area tree.
So, we're gonna have chests over here.
Like that.
We're gonna have more chests, actually.
Turn these into planks.
Chest.
There we go.
And...
Yeah, that's good.
We even have a chest here as well.
Let's have one over here.
There we go.
This is going to be...
Let's say this one is like blocks, like this.
You know?
Just blocks, like that.
Easy to remember.
Then we need something like...
I can't start sorting two...
What do you call it specifically right now?
It needs to be a little grainy.
That's not the right word.
You know what I mean.
Let's actually start cooking some of this.
In you go.
In.
We have a bunch of food we can cook.
And a bunch of iron.
Ooh, 42.
Nice.
Let's make a diamond pickaxe!
Do we have any...
Oh, I used all my wood.
Okay.
Chop down a tree then.
We need sticks and stones.
Dick is like this.
Can we just make a bunch?
Yeah.
48.
And then get a little bit more wood.
And then I have to remember exactly what it takes to make that saw.
Oh!
And we gotta make slabs at some point.
Because that's apparently important.
I forgot what it unlocked.
Oh yeah!
The windmill thingy!
We need slabs for the windmill.
So that's also something we gotta do.
Pickaxe.
Boom.
We're gonna throw away the old.
Put it over here.
Actually, no.
I'm gonna make a little throwaway hole.
Throwaway hole is going to be...
Here.
Things go down there.
There we go.
And immediately we're also gonna make a tiny farm here.
This is like the preliminary farm.
In fact, we call this area preliminary right now.
That's the word.
Word of the day.
I'm gonna make...
Oh!
I need a hole for that.
Do I go diamond hole immediately?
Woo!
Put a diamond on the hole?
No.
I need an axe first before anything else.
There we go.
And now we throw this away in the hole?
Wait.
Where's the hole?
There we go.
There it is.
Axe.
Boom.
Good.
Oh, they're cooking.
I love seeing that.
All right.
Uh, mis...
Miscellaneous is gonna be in here.
So that's all stuff like...
Uh...
This, you know?
Oh, I need these actually.
So stuff like that.
And leather.
And books.
You know, random crap.
That we don't need right now.
Don't need all this food either right now.
We have 24 steaks.
We're totally chilling.
Now we make a...
Hole.
A diamond hole.
That also beautifully removes all our...
Diamonds, so we don't have any left.
Clean inventory.
Okay.
Tiny farm.
It's going to be...
Where do I put it?
Actually, I removed this tree.
And put it right here.
I didn't like this tree anyway.
Wait a second.
Make water here.
I like that.
Actually, wait.
I'm gonna hate this later.
How do I get...
Turned them into non...
Okay, it's gonna go back.
I'm gonna do it over here instead.
Maybe here.
Eh, it's not the most beautiful thing ever, but...
It'll have to do.
Okay, now we need a bucket.
Oh!
Go to bed!
Are you done cooking?
Not yet.
So much iron.
Oh, look at all these steaks.
Wonderful.
We can even cook more.
No, we can't.
Actually, I will eat these first.
With all this, we're gonna make armor now.
Wait, I have those already.
So many chest, head, and legs.
Chest.
Wait.
Chest?
Yeah.
Chest.
Wait, how did that...
I searched for H-E-A, and it somehow knew I was going for a helmet.
Oh, maybe H-E for hel...
Okay, yeah.
Maybe.
Boots.
I was like, does it read my mind?
Yeah!
Suit it up!
Wonderful.
Let me throw away this crap.
Anything else I need to make?
Maybe...
Nah, that's good for now.
I like it.
Arrows are going in here.
Oh, emeralds also.
Wood situation is beautiful.
Boat.
We...
Yeah, keep that on me.
That's actually good.
Really want to put this gold in here.
Then we need a...
What else did we need?
How's our shield going?
Okay, we still have durability on that.
Bucket.
We need that one.
And...
Let's get some water.
There's water over here.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, this...
Dude, this spot is freaking perfection.
We even have turtles and shit?
Yeah!
Not bad, huh?
I'm glad I took the time to look for the proper spot.
You know what, actually?
We start by doing this.
Here.
And we need one more water.
And then we have infinite water.
I'll know all the tricks.
There we go.
So now we can go like this.
One more.
There we go.
Wonderful.
Now, I also had some bones.
I will use those.
Make this.
Isn't that beautiful?
Yeah!
I'll even go a little bit further with it.
Good!
Isn't that beautiful?
Now we have that taken care of.
I'm actually going to make a little something nice here.
I mean, it is a work area, but let's keep it a little neat anyway.
You know?
A little neat working area.
We can even have a little torch on it.
Boom.
Minimalist architecture.
Good.
Alright!
We got some wheat now.
Let's throw that in there.
The gold is probably ready to be cooked.
We have the bucket if we need it.
Boat.
Oh, yeah.
This...
Dude, I'm feeling so good about this.
Alright, let's start building, huh?
So, uh...
We definitely need...
Uh...
Wait, did I make my zinc?
Oh, I didn't even do that!
Yo!
Hold on.
Fuck the gold.
Zinc time!
In fact, can we make a blaster?
How do we make a blast furnace?
Blast furnace, blast furnace.
Is it...
Is it, uh...
We need this for it?
No, that's the anvil.
Okay.
Anvil.
And...
That's it.
Maybe it's something stupid like...
Uh...
Smooth...
Oh, smooth stone maybe, actually.
How do I do that again?
I think we need to cook this.
Yeah, look at this.
We unlock new stuff now.
So we do that first, and then we have to cook it again, I believe?
I'm not entirely sure, though, that it's smooth stone.
But it's something that looks like this one.
Actually, maybe it's just stone.
Is it just stone?
No?
Let me try this.
Is that the one?
Slaps.
Oh!
We got it!
Blast me!
Oh, that's...
Okay, we need a lot of that.
I don't think we have enough, actually.
We also gotta cook this zinc.
So what do we just unlock here?
Oh, we need to make nuggets!
That's right!
Chicken McNuggets.
And I can turn them back if I want to.
But I don't want to.
Cheers, guys!
So we need three smooth stone, and...
Let me see here.
Iron ingots and furnace.
So another furnace.
Oh, that means we need more stone.
Let me go get that real quick.
Oh, that cave looks delicious as well!
Look at it, man!
Wait.
Okay.
Sounded like the music just went out.
But I'm just imagining things.
I need more stone.
But I don't want to...
Do I really have to...
Go down there to get that?
Isn't there some stone that isn't in the big scary hole?
Fine.
Please don't fall down and die.
Okay.
That's enough.
Now we can also make a little nice path up again.
Yeah, that's good.
Also, let me take off this shield.
Oh!
Look at that viewport now.
Oh, man.
When you get used to the shield, you forget how it is without it.
Woo!
Much better.
Smooth stone.
Blasting time.
Ah, not yet.
First we furnace.
Blast.
So, anyway.
I started blasting.
Let's put that...
Here.
Actually, no.
We're gonna put these next to each other.
All the furnace thingies are over here.
Crafting table is...
There.
Yeah!
Not bad.
Okay.
Give me some of these now.
In.
Give me...
There.
And then in this one...
We're gonna blast this zinc.
Lovely.
Okay.
So, I put all my oars over here.
Keep the zinc nuggets, actually.
Smooth stone.
Block of iron.
Let's keep these.
Maybe this one goes in here now.
Iron ingot.
I'll probably need it, right?
Let's keep all the exploration stuff down here in the right.
Yeah, this counts as exploration stuff.
Da-da-da-da.
Oh, yeah.
Look at us now.
We're totally rolling.
Let's use these to full advantage.
We can cook some copper at the same time.
Okay.
So, what do we need to make?
Now that we have that...
Uh...
Nuggets...
Andesite!
Is what we need.
Yes.
Andesite alloy!
Boom!
Yeah!
Look at all that crap.
Oh, that's a lot, actually.
Now we're cooking.
Give me that.
What's next?
Let's do...
Oh, we can make the basin.
Hand crank!
Oh, we gotta make that.
Take it!
Yes!
And we're gonna have...
Let's make a basin.
Wonderful.
Okay.
What else?
Shaft?
Definitely need shafts.
Let's make a lot.
I know I'm gonna need those.
And...
What else?
What can I make but don't have the resources for?
Ooh, that's a lot.
No...
Oh!
Sail!
Windmill sail!
We need more alloys.
We're not done alloying.
Also, go to bed.
Notice, by the way!
No monsters!
Because I cordoned off the area.
Feels good, yo.
Let's make more of these.
Boink!
That's a lot!
Alloy time.
46 alloys.
Oh, that reminds me!
We need to do this!
Let's do it to this tree.
And then...
Boink, boink, boink!
Ha ha!
Yes!
Wonderful.
Like that.
And then we do that.
Nice!
Very good.
These are cooking as well.
I'm gonna leave that for now.
This one doesn't need to do anything.
Maybe the hole I leave in here.
For now.
Yeah.
Just taking up space.
Basin.
Okay.
What do I need to make now?
Encased chain drive.
No, no, no.
We're gonna make the...
The windmill.
Oh!
Slaps!
We gotta slab it up.
That's the key.
Slap, slab, slab.
Show me the slaps.
I just give me six.
Okay, so let's see.
That's the one.
Yep, we got it.
Windmill something.
Windmill bearing.
Diorite?
Oh, it's any block?
Slap shaft.
Wait, what?
Why can't I...
Do we need this?
Okay.
Andesite?
Okay, fine.
I think I spent all my andesite.
That's crazy.
I really can't make it?
What?
Okay.
Let's go find some andesite.
Actually, I see diorite.
I'll take that.
There's a use for diorite now.
Maybe take a bit more.
How do I get back up, though?
That
works.
Make it easy for future me.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Now I should be able to make it.
Yes, dude.
We got the windmill.
Oh, but wait.
I probably need to go chop down some trees first.
So...
Wait, no.
That's not the one.
I need a saw.
Saw, saw, saw.
I could also make this now.
Wait.
Oh, shit.
I made the wrong one.
I made the same mistake last time.
I'm actually going to put my create stuff in here.
Maybe I'll use this.
Keep this here.
Leave this in here for now.
Yeah.
And...
Probably don't need all of these at the moment.
Oh, man.
The inventory management is already so much superior than last time.
Crazy.
Right.
No.
What was it I wanted to do?
It was something I wanted to do.
Oh, yeah.
The axe.
No, the saw.
Saw.
I need to saw things.
I don't think I can actually make it yet.
Wait.
What did I do to actually be able to make that?
I think I just created a bunch of things and hoped for the best.
This is the one we need for the...
The bonker.
Shaft we made.
Let's make some wheels.
Make like...
Ten of these.
We're also going to need the small one.
Cog.
Need more wood.
Grab a bit more wood.
I just want to make ten of each.
Oh, that was the thingy.
The spinny thing.
Gearbox.
Gantry carriage.
I can make that?
Do I even need to make that right now?
I don't think I do.
All I want to do right now is to get a saw so I can get wood so I can make my house.
That's the first step right now.
A turntable?
Can I start DJing or what?
That would be kind of dope.
What else can I make?
Dude, I forgot what I made last...
Oh, let's get the...
My wool.
Mail.
Sale.
Sticks and andesite alloy.
That we have.
So we just need sticks.
We can make it.
40 sticks.
Oh, we can make a lot of this.
Let me see.
Let's make...
Good.
I mean, I could set this up now, but I need to connect it to something for it to make sense, right?
I mean, we could just start spinning for no reason, but...
There's got to be a reason for it.
At least.
I mean, worst case, we have it ready for when we need it.
Millstone.
Oh, I made that one, didn't I?
Maybe that's part of the unlock.
We can make a millstone.
Andesite casing.
Oh, we need some kind of weird...
Maybe diorite works there.
It totally does!
Very nice.
And we unlocked a bunch of new shit there.
Like what?
How did you get through my perimeter?
Sir?
Oh my god.
Jesus.
He actually set fire to me.
Jump in the water!
Okay, we're good.
We're good.
Dude.
One bone for all this is insane.
But...
But I didn't unlock anything new, though.
Like, this is not gonna lead me to the saw.
That's the problem.
What else did I make?
Wait, package filter?
Matches packaged items...
Oh, they're...
Yeah, this sounds insane.
Like, what do you mean address?
Whoa.
Let's make this one.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, now we unlocked a lot of shit.
Let me see.
Remind me.
How that works.
Maybe we just need to produce some of that stuff.
You know, and then we'll figure it out.
Let's actually do that.
So, that means we need a windmill!
I'm actually so happy about that.
Because I love the windmill.
I'm gonna add
more sails to it this time.
Make it spin faster.
Put the stuff in there.
Keep that one.
The slaps, I don't like those either.
Let's have them in here.
Got some locks.
Good.
So, let's see if we remember this.
We needed to have the thingy.
Windmill bearing.
And then we needed a wheel.
Shafts.
Small wheels.
Wait, why do I have nine?
Shouldn't I have ten?
I'm pretty sure I made ten.
Maybe that was used in a construction of something that I did.
Yeah, probably.
Oh, maybe the millstone.
Has a wheel on it, I guess.
Let's put that in here for now.
Okay, so I think we want to do large cog wheel into windmill bearing, right?
So, I need to go to this tree.
I don't like this tree.
This tree is triggering me.
Big wheel time.
Right there.
No.
Let's have it
maybe right down here next to this thing.
Nah, I like it right here, actually.
This is good.
I'm overthinking it a little bit here, for sure.
Now we put this one on top.
I think?
No, wait.
This doesn't look right.
This looks wrong.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let me think.
That's gonna spin.
Spins that one.
Yeah.
Looks good.
We put this one on top.
Now we put the sails.
Right, and I'm gonna right click this.
That's true.
Get rid of this tree.
Oh, we haven't found birch yet.
Dude, being able to build up like that is actually so huge.
Oh, yeah.
Are you ready for the spin?
We're about to spin like crazy.
We can add like this.
I think I need more.
It's not the most beautiful ever, but I mean, it works.
Not that bad.
And then...
Yeah, dude!
Look at that.
Wait, it doesn't seem like it's spinning faster than the last one I did.
I thought for sure now that I have more sails on that it would spin faster.
Oh, well.
Alright.
Let's do this and we're gonna bring it into...
Actually, no.
The other side.
There.
Because then I want to put a big wheel on...
Oh, let's do this.
Hold on.
Watch this.
Oh, nah.
Maybe a big wheel on top now?
No.
We put it below.
Definitely below.
That works.
Then a small wheel.
And then here.
And then...
Actually, we could also just use a rod.
Or a shaft.
Like that.
Wheel.
And then...
Are you ready?
Depot.
Here.
Press.
Oops.
Gimme.
Oh, shit.
It's the other way.
Crap.
I keep mixing it up.
Dang it.
Alright.
So...
Because it's the other way...
Then we wanna...
Well, we still wanna do this gear down here for sure.
We can get that speed.
Good speed now.
Now we gotta translate that into a...
Big one.
Oops.
That doesn't work.
Oh, no.
I'm feeling the fever coming on already.
The dream sequence is initiating.
And I don't like it.
Oh, shit.
Wait, how the...
Oh, wait.
Gearbox is a thing, right?
That's what we need to do.
That was a whole trick.
Vertical gearbox.
So now...
That's it.
Now we gearbox it.
I mean, it's ugly as hell.
I don't like the way that looks.
But...
We can hide it.
Hey, that actually looks amazing!
What the fuck?
You can do that?
Blows my mind.
Whoa!
Okay!
Hold up.
That's amazing.
Ah, stop.
Yes!
It's...
Oh, it even looks good, too!
Yo...
Okay, okay.
Let's go press some stuff.
So, hold on.
Uh...
I can make a dirt path out of that.
Iron sheets.
Okay.
I have iron.
Maybe that's the thing I needed to do.
I should not do it out of everything, though.
Just some of it.
Press it!
Oh, I...
Bonk!
More.
Hey, dude.
I love this.
I love this little thing down here.
That looks so good.
Wow.
And we unlocked...
The saw!
The saw is unlocked!
That is what we needed, baby.
Fantastic!
Let's go bonk some gold as well.
Are you done bonking?
Now you are.
Nice.
Yeah!
Okay.
So now let me see the saw.
Uh, saw.
Okay.
Didn't I have some more andeside casing?
I have one.
But what else did I need?
One?
I...
Oh, wait.
Did I...
See, good thing I left some.
You know?
I had the presence of mind there.
The saw is ours, and we got the hand crank.
Are you ready to crank it?
I'm taking this and that.
Food is over here.
Put the food in there.
This one in as well.
I'm actually gonna bring this with me.
I like having dirt.
Let's bring the good food.
Eat.
It's the middle of the night, and there's no zombies or anything, because I have a perimeter.
What a feeling.
Um, I should really do this.
Then grab the alloys.
And now this one is done bonking?
No, don't bonk my axe.
Ah!
That's the toolbox!
Actually, let's bring that with us!
Let's make a toolbox.
We can store stuff in this.
Leather, cog, wheel, and chest.
I have all that.
No problem.
Just one leather.
Chest.
Tool.
Cheeto!
Toolbox.
Yeah.
Let's do it.
So watch this.
We're gonna bring this with us?
And we're just gonna fill this up with wood?
How incredible is that?
I love it.
Love the little animation on it, too, when it opens and closes.
That's nice.
That goes right there.
Mm-mm!
Very good.
All right.
You can go in here now.
Same with that.
Shaft.
We're gonna throw you in here.
Wait, where did I put my...
Was it here?
Yeah, I guess it was.
Put him there.
The saw comes with me, so that means the hand crank comes with me as well.
Shield, of course.
Put that on immediately.
Food?
Check.
Cogwheels are inside.
Boat is also coming with us.
I forgot we had birch log.
We can turn that into this.
Oh, yeah.
Wait, the saw can also be used on...
Wait, hold on a minute.
Antisite alloy into six shafts.
Is that better?
Wait a minute.
Holy shit.
It is way more efficient to use the saw for that.
Wow.
How does that even work, though?
Like, physically, how do I...
Do it?
Okay.
Oh!
Gym.
I can't wait to activate the gym today.
We are gonna have a gym today.
It's coming.
Okay.
Block cutting.
Antisite scaffolding.
Why would you have that?
I guess to have it look more...
construction-y.
Copycat step?
Hmm.
So it's like...
It's simply a better...
saw.
Because, you know, the...
Vanilla saw...
is still a thing.
Or the stonecutter, right?
It's just not as good, I guess.
Okay.
In you go.
Saplings.
Look at me organizing my inventory here.
Hmm.
Not bad.
I'm gonna keep the oak planks on me.
Sticks are coming with me too.
Bucket is always good to have.
We should make a couple more torches for sure.
I have coal, right?
Some.
Ooh.
We unlock some new stuff.
Oh.
We can press it.
Turn it into sheets.
I guess we can do that with some of them.
Let's put 15 in there.
Bonk for me!
Oh my god.
That is just so satisfying.
Oh yeah.
No, I wanted these to make...
torches.
I mean, we probably don't need torches right now.
Because we're going...
wood cutting.
But, you know, it's good to have.
Andesite casing here.
Toolboxes with me.
Planks.
So anything I'm missing.
We got attacks.
We got defense.
We got shield.
We got food.
Boat.
We got the hand crank.
Actually, let's get ready with the keybinds on that one.
Let's have it on...
these two.
See?
Yeah.
Put the boat there.
I think we're ready.
But, here's the thing.
How do we find our way back?
That's the problem right now.
So, if I go off into somewhere, you know...
There were thick threes in this direction.
So, I definitely want to go and chop those down.
The thing is, though...
The problem is...
How do I know how to get back?
Maybe a steam wizard going, telling me where I am?
Where my base is?
I don't know.
Maybe I can make a remote control and fire a rocket in the distance.
You know, I'm lost and I go, beep.
And then the rocket in the distance goes, pshh.
Like a flare.
And it'll show me where the base is.
I don't know if that's a thing.
Oh, man.
All right.
I'm just gonna go.
So, let me see.
That's east.
So, I'm going south now.
I'm trying to remember the area here.
So, we go south towards the water.
Thick trees are there.
Dude, I love my spot here.
I love that I went here.
What a spot.
Cheers on that.
Okay.
We need a lot of wood.
And I mean a lot.
Let me just remember this area.
I'm actually gonna put a torch.
Here.
Should have put a torch on the other side as well.
We're still going south.
South, south, south.
Until we reach the big chonky trees.
How about I...
Why did I do that?
That's super risky.
What if I died?
I couldn't resist.
Sometimes I can't stop myself.
Are you ready to crank it?
Here we go.
You ready?
Oh, my God.
Wait a minute.
Hold on a sec.
Let me ponder on that one.
Explain that to me.
Oh.
Oh, that's actually kind of cool.
So when it's upward phasing...
Okay.
No, no.
Show me...
Here we go.
When given rotational force, a mechanical saw will cut trees.
Oh, maybe it's only the single line...
No, no.
Definitely.
Yeah, look at this.
In order to cut the tree fully, the saw has to break the last block.
Oh!
Okay.
Say no more, fam.
I get that.
Wait, no.
Guys, I'm gonna extract some sap.
Wrong button.
Okay.
So, wait.
We have to...
Oh, that makes so much sense, actually.
Crank that shit!
Simba!
Oh, yeah, dude.
I love this saw so much.
Oh, yeah.
Let's put it on again.
Get rid of that one.
C-V.
Crank that shit!
We're gonna have more than enough in no time.
I wish they would go in the same spots here, though, every time, you know?
So, uh...
So I don't have to keep doing this.
But whatever.
Ah, wait, wait.
Not yet, not yet.
Oh, yeah.
Beautiful.
Come to papa.
We even get all the saplings and apples and shit.
Nope, wrong way.
I have to sit down and do it.
That's the rule.
Dude, there's so much.
I could even start prioritizing the tallest trees.
There's a chonky one over there.
Oh, this one is good.
This one is good.
Tell me that isn't the sexiest thing you've ever seen.
Let's not do everything in one spot.
I'm gonna spread it out a bit, you know?
Yeah.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
If I get some bone meal, we can really accelerate this.
With the saplings, right?
So that's coming up.
Oh, we gotta get some bone meal first.
Which means we gotta kill some skeletons.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Realized too late.
Dang.
You know, I should have left it.
And just destroyed the other ones.
I love to crank it.
Crank it up.
Dude, just a...
...sound, you know?
Because everything breaks at once.
It's overwhelming the senses in the best way.
Oh, that's a big chongus.
Oh, yeah.
It's gonna be a sexy one.
But I want even bigger trees.
Like, this is not big for me.
I want more.
Oh, whoa.
Wait, are these connected?
I wonder how that works then.
Check this out.
We're gonna experiment.
Guys, prediction.
Do you think both will break or just one?
They're connected.
I say...
Both will break.
There we go.
Okay, so none of us were right.
It's like somewhere in between.
That's weird.
That doesn't...
Okay, I don't...
It doesn't compute.
That's the most unexpected outcome of all.
You know, I kind of want to leave this tree like it is here.
As a sign that I was here, you know?
I chopped this tree off right there.
Wonderful.
Let's get another big one.
Oh, we got a ghostly...
Oh, I forgot the pet!
Major mistake.
One last tree.
There's one.
And then we go.
I'm being a little greedy.
Dude, it sounded like someone came...
Ah!
Running at me, dude!
Fuck me!
The hell?
Didn't that sound like some footsteps coming at me?
Jesus Christ.
Alright, I'm leaving.
Wow.
And then I scared myself by cracking right after because...
I thought that was a monster.
That creeper encounter has me scarred for life.
Or at least for the next 50 minutes.
At least.
Oh!
Why do I do it?
Hey, I need you.
I need you.
Okay.
I don't need you anymore.
Oh, one more.
I'll kill you.
There's my light.
Eat.
Man.
Chopping wood all day really makes you hungry, huh?
Your mommy is dead.
I can't stop thinking about that blimmy clip.
Oh, you know what, actually?
Let me kill you.
Maybe there's something we can do with the...
Oh my god.
Jeez.
Hey!
There we go.
Okay, we got some dye.
Ink sack.
That was a very successful little expedition.
And it took no time at all.
And look at all this wood.
You're so ready to build.
It's gonna look a little weird, I guess.
Because we're using dark oak locks.
In a bright oak lock location.
I wonder if that is illegal.
We can make it look good.
Yeah.
Let's just sort the inventory real quick.
Sticks.
Smoke it up.
Ink sack is definitely miscellaneous.
I forgot about the toolbox.
I should have...
Well, not that I had trouble with my inventory.
But, you know.
There we go.
Okay.
Let's get going, shall we?
Boom.
Wait a sec.
Wait a minute.
Can I maybe be more efficient here?
Wait a sec.
No, no.
I need to check...
What was it called?
Dark oak...
Stripped...
Planks.
No, I...
Okay.
I don't know how to make these yet, I guess.
Shit.
Ah, well.
It's not that it's hard to, you know...
Do.
Okay.
I actually made a lot.
Damn.
Okay.
We're gonna leave these as, like, the foundational parts.
Like, pillars and stuff.
Let's start making the floor.
I have no idea what's gonna happen here.
We're just gonna go for it.
Let's see what happens.
We'll start by making the floor.
Just cover this entire hole.
And then we build the house around that.
That way, I'm also not limiting myself to a rectangle.
You know?
I'm being forced to be a little creative with it.
Which is good for me.
Although we'd be...
Probably we should have, like, a double floor.
Not that I think about it.
Just for safety reasons.
Yeah, actually, I'm gonna do that.
Maybe even a triple floor.
Yeah, let's make a triple floor.
Ultimate triple floor.
It's gonna take a lot of planks, but we have a lot, so...
We have plenty, actually.
Oh, man.
I really fucked this up.
I should have done this in a different way, shouldn't I?
Wait, we just start by making this level, and then we...
Oh, dude, obviously.
I get it, though.
And we jump on that level, right?
That's the whole way to do it.
Yes.
Oh, much better.
Much better.
Dude, I'm actually so excited about this house!
This is...
One of the more unique ones I've made.
Or...
I'm making.
It excites me!
Okay, I just wanna do that, and then here.
The reason I'm doing this is...
If there's somehow...
It's gonna be a creeper in my house later, and it's gonna blow a hole, at least I won't fall down to my death, you know?
Assuming I survived the explosion.
You never know what's gonna happen.
Dude!
So, apparently...
Uh...
Or...
Allegedly...
There's gonna be an elevator in the game.
Somehow we can make it.
And I'm gonna elevator myself down.
If it even works...
In a straight line like that, I don't know.
We'll have to see.
I can't stop thinking about the elevator.
Dude, I have so much wood left, I really thought I would be...
Needing more, but I really don't.
Now we're definitely safe.
We're not gonna fall in this hole.
But you know what I could do, actually?
I could make a little pool at the very bottom.
So that if I were to fall, I'd just fall into water!
Yo, that's actually...
Freaking genius!
And you know what?
I kinda like this look, with the dark oak here.
I think it looks sick.
Okay, so...
Let's use these oak logs.
And do I have my...
I don't have that.
I need my hoe!
And my wheat is coming along nicely.
I love it.
That's good.
Now, obviously, it doesn't have to be limited to just this area here.
We can always expand.
But for now, I'm gonna...
Put it in the shape of the hole.
Right.
Okay, so...
Let me actually think.
What is the best way to lay a foundation for a house?
Because I always end up fucking this up somehow.
I need to really think about it.
I guess I start by laying out the rooms I want.
We can even do it with this.
So, let's say...
Hmm.
How do I want to do this?
I guess I can just sort of do...
Something like this here?
Let's make the outline around this first.
And then we take it from there.
Yeah, see?
That's not good.
That's a little ugly.
So, we're gonna overshoot a little bit here.
Nothing wrong with that.
Oh!
We can mill that one!
I don't know what that's gonna be.
Okay, I like this shape so far!
Shape is good.
That's starting to be a little...
Too straight for me.
Maybe this here we can change...
Slightly.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Look at this.
I
mean, I don't know how it's gonna look, but we'll see.
Not bad!
I may even wanna...
Take this one further here.
That's too much.
And then over here...
I think I'm gonna go into the dirt.
You gotta stay a little rectangular, you know?
It is a house.
Dude, I am so freaking hyped!
About everything that's gonna happen.
We just go...
Straight in.
Yeah, I like that!
And then we go all into the dirt.
I love it, I love it.
That's a sick start.
I love it.
We're gonna make this a little different over here.
There.
That's pretty cool!
Huh?
I like...
I
like...
Something like that, you know?
I don't know.
Yeah.
Sick.
Oh,
yeah.
And now, we have to decide on the pillars!
Let's also go to bed.
Cheers.
I do love my pillar design here.
Oh, but wait a minute.
Let me think.
If I do pillars there...
Uh...
How did I do...
I made a house in the second season that was so good.
Where I did the pillars in a funky way.
So I had them, like...
A little bit out, you know what I mean?
Um...
Wait.
How does it look if I just do this?
No, I definitely need to...
Like...
Here, you know?
Yeah.
We have to...
We have to extend it one.
Like this.
Or we do it...
No.
If I just put the pillar here, it's gonna look a little too...
Okay, I actually like this, I think.
And then here.
Guess that would be there.
A little funky there.
Let's move this out just a tad bit.
Do we have any planks?
We do.
I like this looks weird.
I like these, but this one...
I mean, I could just not do it.
But let me see how it looks just with these first.
Then I can decide.
That means it's this one.
Yeah.
Like, this is too close.
Maybe I just skipped that one.
Yeah.
This is good for now.
Let's put in some more walls.
Get rid of this tree.
We're gonna make a proper roof this time around as well.
None of that bullshit...
That we did in the last stream.
That was ugly as hell.
I admit it.
No flat roof.
Or maybe we do like a whole new invention.
We're not gonna do the...
I'll see.
I'll have to think about it.
I'm just saying.
Maybe we try something completely new.
Like, no roof at all.
It's like a modern design where we, you know, embrace the weather.
We like the elements.
We're probably not gonna do that.
We can also incorporate different types of wood.
To spice it up, you know.
And maybe include some stone as well.
This is just the frame right now.
We're making the frame.
And then we'll decide later how to...
Embellish it, you know?
We're gonna have a second story, of course.
Okay, after this...
We're gonna take a look at it from outside.
See what it looks like.
Yeah, I don't like these, actually.
I like them on the outside.
Not on the inside.
Like this one.
Okay.
Let's see what it looks like.
Actually, I kind of do like this.
Maybe I'll do it on some corners.
And not others.
It's definitely a very brown house.
Yep.
I mean, it's not bad.
I can dig it.
If we put in some windows, some embellishments.
This is definitely just the beginning.
And the coolest part is there's a cave right below here.
I still...
Like, that is so freaking cool.
We can have an infinitely...
What do you call it?
Not tall...
The opposite of tall basement.
You know what I mean?
Now I'm inside, and...
Roof should be one higher.
One higher.
Oh!
Now I know what to do.
We need to make, like, horizontal...
Log sections as well.
Right?
And you know what?
Maybe we do it on every...
Oh, this is what I did.
I remember now.
I did this on my house in the second season.
Where I...
For every, um...
What do you call it?
Layer?
We have horizontal...
You know?
Let me think.
Uh...
So that would be the floor.
So here...
Would be it.
Ah!
Fell down.
We can even sort of...
Extend it out like that.
Maybe that's crazy.
Maybe I hate it.
We'll see.
Let's keep it like this for now.
So this is the roof.
Roof.
Uh...
It can even do something like that.
You see this?
How it sort of...
Does that?
Ooh, that's...
That's kind of...
That's bold.
That's sexy.
That's...
Maybe a little bit illegal.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Not sure how I feel about that.
Yeah, these corners are weird.
Guys.
We're gonna have the andesite...
Uh...
Casing...
Floor.
Because the floor from the last house we made was actually kind of killer.
We're definitely doing that.
Just to switch up the colors as well.
Because this is getting way too...
Same-ish.
You know?
Actually, I really should be doing this then.
Just to keep it consistent.
Yo, that actually kind of slaps that corner right there!
Whoa!
I like it.
Let's make a door.
Mi casa.
Mi casa e...
Mi casa e, uh...
Uh...
Bello.
Ha ha ha!
I probably butchered that a little bit.
I don't even know if I said it right.
Whatever.
Okay.
Uh, what now?
I guess this is the floor.
So, this is probably...
We're gonna, you know...
Andesite that one as well.
But, if we need a lot of the andesite stuff, guys...
We cannot be doing that manually.
There's gotta be a way to do that more easily.
Let's think about it.
Andesite ca- Oh, we don't have anything that can produce it then.
Okay.
Not yet, at least.
Oh!
Fuck!
Fuck off.
Actually, I do wanna kill you.
I need your, uh...
Eyeballs.
Your earrings.
What- What are they called?
Uh...
Ender...
Pearls.
I thought Pearl's earring, you know?
Like, I don't know what I thought.
Hoop- Hooplus.
Round objects.
Shit.
I don't know where he went.
He's gone.
Okay.
Let's see.
Uh...
Yeah.
I like this house so far.
I don't like this, actually.
You know what?
We should be doing, um...
Wait, how do I actually hide that?
This is gonna look shit in one direction, isn't it?
No matter what I do.
Uh-oh.
How on earth am I handling this?
There is one way to handle it.
Right there.
You see that?
Now nobody knows.
And it looks cool.
I may change my mind on that.
We'll see.
I do wonder, though.
So, how does the game distinguish a tree from a house?
I'm thinking, what if I took my...
What if I destroyed the bottom layer of my house except one block, and I took my saw to it?
Will that remove the entire house?
Isn't that kind of a cool test?
Someday, maybe, we'll try it.
Okay.
This is looking hella good.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Maybe even inside as well.
On every corner.
We also need some working lights in here.
Getting a little dark.
Much better.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Let's make a little door here, so we can easily go out and in from every angle.
Yes.
I love it.
Oh my god.
The andeside floor here, or roof, ceiling, it's gonna look amazing.
Let's go to bed.
Oop.
Cheers.
Next up.
This goes in.
Don't eat this right now.
Also, don't eat the boat.
Or this one.
How's my crops?
Oh, look at that.
They are growing.
I'm gonna have bread for ages.
Oh, I just got rid of my hole.
I need it again.
You are not...
There we go.
Okay.
What next?
Uh...
Put this wood in here.
Dirt.
We can keep that.
All right.
Maybe I even extend this one further?
Because of the pillars.
Ayyyy.
Actually.
Are we going a little too crazy with this?
Maybe...
Maybe I need to stop.
We'll see how it looks later.
For now, that's fine.
Okay.
Let's think about this andeside situation.
Andeside.
Oh, right.
We have to do the manual thing here.
Andeside.
Well, I guess you would have to...
Right-click a wood.
To, you know, scalp it.
And then after that, you put on the trimmings.
Or whatever.
Wheat flour.
Oh, wait.
Should I be crushing something?
Wait.
Can I crush anything new?
Let me see.
Yeah.
Okay.
Those...
I guess I did that.
Nice.
Okay.
We can make a pipe now.
Very cool.
And that's it.
Got it.
Toolbox.
I mean, I could just go and...
Wee-ya.
Oh, my God.
It's so silly!
It's crazy!
After all these years...
Let's make a door.
But do we want it in dark oak?
I mean...
Ah, it's getting too oaky!
Isn't it?
There's too much oak.
Even the goddamn toolbox is brown.
Everything's too brown here.
I could also...
No, I'm not gonna slap shit.
Okay, calm down.
I'm already getting overwhelmed.
Let me think.
What did I want to do?
Right.
We need to figure out how to automatically make the andeside thingies.
So, let's just start producing some stuff.
Some new stuff.
What have I not produced yet?
Oh, we can make these now.
That's cool.
Whisk.
Wait, schematic table.
Write saved schematics onto an empty schematic.
Uploads a chosen file from your schematics folder?
What?
Wait, how does that even work?
Oh, I need to make a book and quill at some point, too.
Wait, metal girder.
I'm trying to think.
What did I make last time that allowed me to progress even further?
Hey, we can make a birch door.
Wait, what?
No, we can't.
Not yet.
Actually, let's make an oak door.
That's probably gonna look okay.
We'll see how that looks.
Eh.
It's passable.
Passable.
This is construction stuff.
So that means door goes in.
Actually, since I'm doing this now.
Let's make one of each.
Too bright.
Yep.
It's oak.
It was already the sweet spot.
Wonderful.
Right.
So, is there anything I can make?
Maybe slabs I already did make, right?
So that's not gonna unlock anything new.
Saw.
Depot.
What else did I make?
Made a basin as well.
Wait, I can make that out of any wood, right?
I can make that out of any wood, right?
So if I do this...
It's not...
Oh, wait.
The shield is on.
I forgot to take that off as well.
And now I put on the end of side stuff.
That should work.
It's the same block, yeah.
I was like...
Maybe the color changes, but no.
I mean, I'll have to do this, I guess.
Oh, wait.
I can also use stripped dark oak action.
Oh, hold on a minute.
I can totally strip these parts.
That's gonna look pretty dope.
Especially...
This is horrible right now.
Let me just try one.
Oh, wait.
This is not oak.
Oh, it's planks.
Right.
I gotta exchange that then.
I don't have a lot of andesite alloy, though.
So that is...
Wait a minute.
Is there an easier way to make that?
Andesite...
Oh, no.
Not yet, at least.
Andesite alloy.
Nah.
All right.
Fine.
And that's all the alloy.
Wait, what?
What'd you say?
Ah, that's manual item application, though.
That's fine.
I'll just have to do it manually right now.
Let's make some more andesite alloys, then.
We need zinc for that.
Zinc and...
Oh!
Andesite, obviously.
But I don't have that.
So I can't even...
Ah, scheisse.
As a German would say in this situation.
I'm not German.
But they would say it.
I guess I'll go collect some...
Some andesite.
That's the next step here.
Or I just keep building a little bit.
We can start unlocking some things.
Shoot!
Let's make a shoot!
Ingot and two sheets.
Oh, this is exactly what I have.
Perfect.
Processing genius.
That's me.
So we definitely unlock something cool there.
Oh, this is the auger shaft.
I already saw that.
Portable storage...
What is this again?
Let's see.
Moving inventories can be tricky to access with automation.
Oh no.
I'm not interested in this right now.
It is cool, but it's not that cool.
Not right now.
Redstone contact.
Mechanical harvester.
Oh, I want to harvest this over here mechanically.
That's going to happen soon.
And we have the normal stone cutter.
Would I ever use that then?
Because I have the other one.
Oh, it's a stone cutter.
It's not a saw.
Well, it is a saw, but it's like...
Not made for stone.
It's meant for wood.
The one I have.
We can make a barrel.
Probably that's going to unlock something, right?
Slaps and non-slaps.
Oh!
What the fuck is that?
Whoa!
Hold on.
Fluid tank!
That sounds hella dope!
Item vault?
We need iron sheets.
Hold on.
Time for the bonk!
Bonk it!
I am so excited.
Thanks.
Item...
Vault...
Before I ponder on it, let me just see it first.
Okay, I can't click on it.
Hmm.
Maybe I put it wrong.
Maybe it needs to be facing the other way.
Oh, how do I do that?
Ah!
It's probably a redstone thing.
It probably needs power, and then it's going to open.
You know?
It's like a...
It's a safe box.
It's a safe.
Look at it.
Maybe you need a password, or a key card, or something.
Okay, let me see what it is.
Item vaults can be used to store large amounts of items?
However, contents cannot be added or taken manually.
Oh!
Really?
Also, that's a big-ass vault.
You can combine them, it seems.
Any components for item transfer can both insert.
Yeah?
Okay, so they're going in...
with a belt.
And take contents from this container, but how do I...
Okay, but...
What's the point of the vault, then, if it's just a middleman?
That's gotta be like a filter thing.
Wait, what's this?
Next scene.
Item vaults can be combined to increase the total capacity.
Yes.
Although I feel like you should have started off with that.
Their base square can be up to three blocks wide.
Sick.
That is actually so dope.
And grow in length up to three times their diameter.
Okay.
Alright.
So...
We would have to need a belt for that.
But I don't know how to make a belt.
Or whatever it's called.
The thing from Bactorio, you know.
Okay.
Well, that's kind of cool.
Oh, shit.
How did you get through my perimeter?
What a bet.
Okay, let's keep making items.
I want to discover more stuff.
And maybe we'll stumble on something we can use.
Oh, God.
So what else can I make?
And I just made a barrel of all things.
And then that happened, you know?
So let's make something super simple.
Let's just take some ingredients.
Like this.
And maybe also...
Something like this.
Let's see what we can make.
A white seat.
Sit yourself down and enjoy the ride.
We'll anchor a player onto a moving contraption.
Great for static furniture, too.
Comes in a variety of colors.
Yo!
That sounds pretty cool.
I'll make one.
Ah!
Yeah.
I'm sitting on it.
I wonder...
Oh, I can't combine it.
I may need some glue or whatever.
Wait, did I just...
Did I just destroy that?
Give me my thing.
I wonder if that's because it's all simulated now, physically.
They have, like, physics simulation here.
Okay, I don't need this.
There's nothing worse than having a single oak slab.
You can't use it for anything.
It's gonna take up a slot.
And it's just annoying to look at.
It's actually the worst.
Okay, shoot.
Put that here.
Same as these things.
Maybe I keep these for now.
Put the seat in here as well.
Okay.
What else can I make?
Let me go to the very last page.
Let's make a trap door!
Surely that's gonna do something.
Nope.
Pressure plate.
No.
Button?
Wait, I wonder...
Oh, I think it's only stone button that gyms.
Damn.
That's rough.
I don't want them.
We're just testing.
Make a fence.
So useless.
Blast furnace!
Oh, wait.
We already have it.
I'm an idiot.
I just remember...
Oh, yeah.
I needed a blast furnace, but I already got it.
Can make a redstone contact, or...
Let's try and make a metal girder.
Three andesite alloys.
I think I may have used them all.
Yeah.
That's too bad.
Oh!
We have some gold we can cook.
Okay.
Analog lever.
We already know what that is, but let's just put it in here.
We can make a sign.
Let's have it be, like, right here.
Uh, casa.
Uh, night.
New.
Dawn.
Dormitory.
For now, at least.
Throw away the signs.
Forward!
What's going on, friend?
What are you bringing me?
I don't want anything from you.
Move along.
Got ladders.
Let's make a ladder.
Okay.
Does nothing either.
Let's make some staircases.
Probably not gonna do anything either.
I mean, who knows?
Fucking slaps did something.
What should I make?
What about a fluid tank?
Barrel and two copper sheets.
But didn't I use my barrel already?
I think I did.
Yeah.
I think we got everything we can do right now.
With what I have.
I mean, I can buy this.
Or make this, I guess.
Chain conveyor.
But that sounds complicated.
Like, I don't even have a...
An idea how this is even gonna work, you know?
This seems cool.
Shaft.
Wait, did...
Maybe the drill?
Did we make that yet?
Oh, we don't have this.
I mean, we can't really do anything without the...
Andesite alloys.
So we just gotta...
Go out and find...
Some.
These ones are also kind of important, I guess.
We can try and make those.
Rope pulley.
Radial chassis.
Yeah, they all need Andesite alloy.
Okay.
It has been decided.
We're gonna go find some Andesite.
But first, a quick break.
I gotta go feed my cat.
And...
Grab another drink.
I'll see you in a bit.
All right.
Cat has been fed.
I have been hydrated.
Now's the time for an expedition.
Isn't that right, Stuart?
Sure is.
Okay, let's pull all this in here.
Actually, I'm gonna bring some wood.
Good to have.
Steaks are good.
I do wanna bring this instead, actually.
I have way more of it.
Rest is good.
So, the goal with this expedition...
We're gonna bring the toolbox.
The goal is to find some Andesite.
Potentially also find some bookshelves.
Because I wanna start enchanting my stuff.
Slightly, at least.
Bring these.
Don't need that one.
Do need this.
And boat.
What did I forget last time?
Oh yeah, bet.
I can actually make one.
But I don't have to bring that every time.
Bet.
Bring the bet.
On with the shield.
Don't need the wool.
Toolboxes here.
And stick.
Now, let's leave that there.
Maybe we want a bit more torches.
Yep.
I like it.
That's good.
Oh, and I wanna find...
Oh, the...
I was about to say signal scope.
But the...
The eyedropper.
The...
Fuck.
Oh, the super.
You know what I mean.
Fuck.
Okay.
I'm going north.
Is this north?
Let me just confirm.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Let's go.
Pray there's nothing I have forgotten.
It's gonna be a little bit of a longer expedition.
And we are gonna make sure that we can find our way home.
Let's see what we can find here.
We can also find a trial chamber.
What's going on over there?
That's a weird looking mountain.
Look how rectangular that is.
Is that a pig?
It sure is.
Oh!
I should have made, uh...
The boots that made me zinc.
So I can ex...
You know what?
I'm gonna go back.
Because I want to go...
Freaking caving.
Without the fear of enemies.
Ah, but then...
Yeah.
In that case, I want to crank my, uh...
Tank.
So we gotta make a tank as well.
The thing is, though, I don't think we actually can make a tank yet.
But surely we can...
Unlo- Oh!
Unlock it!
Fuck!
Dude, I thought someone's gonna rip me down and...
Or pull me down into the water.
I don't know what I thought.
It's just one of those bubbly things.
Fucking sounds.
You know, if...
I've said this before, but if Minecraft had more just ambient sounds...
You wouldn't get jump scared as much in this game.
Because listen...
There's nothing.
Not even the rustle of water.
Or the...
Is that the right...
Verb there?
Probably not.
What a bit.
Sweet dreams.
Oh, it's a turtle.
We need to go breathing underwater.
We need the...
The headpiece and the tank.
Please tell me I can make the tank.
Oh, wait.
It's...
Oh...
Not quite.
But, maybe I just need to make the headpiece.
Then we unlock the tank.
Maybe that's how that went.
Let me see.
Head.
Dive...
Diving?
Oh, this one.
Copper diving boots.
Copper ingot andesite...
Oh, andesite alloy!
God damn...
Okay, I'm gonna go inside my hole.
Um...
In fact...
Watch this.
Get ready.
Uh, wait a second.
I also need to go up again.
Let me bring...
Oh my god, Stuart.
No, that's...
Fine.
I'll find some ascension.
Yeah, it's okay.
Here we go!
You ready?
Oh!
What the fuck me, dude?
You were waiting for me!
Fucking hell, try to shit on my parade.
Oh, there's a creeper as well.
Okay then.
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
Yikes.
Wow.
There's another creeper!
I need a bow.
And I need it now.
Is he gonna fall on me?
Okay, we can't have creepers up there.
That is just...
Not okay.
I gotta light that place.
Don't explode, you asshole!
Light it up!
No more spawning down here.
I forbid it.
None.
There we go.
Much better.
I'll take care of that later.
Alright, let's go explore this cave, shall we?
Find some andesite.
That's the mission right now.
I also see some iron.
Tell me it's a nice cave.
I hope it's not a shit cave.
Oh, it's looking like a nice cave.
I think they're in the floor.
Yeah, definitely something.
I hear you.
Never mind, I don't.
Whatever.
I need to find crystals down here.
Oh, and andesite.
And who knows?
Maybe I'll need a lot of gold as well.
Like, I don't really know what these components are gonna be requiring.
There's these zinc up there.
That is still something I need.
Not as much as andesite, though.
In fact, am I going too far down to even find andesite?
Oh, wait a minute.
This cave is amazing looking.
There's even more stuff down there.
Yo.
We found the perfect spot to make a house.
This is incredible looking.
Wait, what the frick is this?
We got some new stuff here.
Calcite.
Wait, that's not new.
Oh.
Not new at all.
But this is new.
Limestone.
Wait, is that new?
I don't remember.
Is this...
I don't know if it's new.
Maybe it's new.
Put it back.
It sure looks new, because I just don't remember seeing stuff like this, you know?
Oh.
Hey, what's up, buddy?
Oh, what a shot.
Wait.
This is literally a bat cave.
Underneath my house.
Am I Batman?
Dang, dude.
Wait, where is this lead?
Oh, my God.
There's a creeper over there.
I'll take some redstone.
I don't know how much this...
Create stuff makes use of redstone.
I mean, I've seen some stuff that utilizes it already, but the extent of it, I'm not sure.
I'm definitely very intrigued by redstone-adjacent objects.
Being a redstone enjoyer.
It's raining through the diorite.
No, it's not.
Optical illusion.
Like, isn't this kind of atmospheric?
Look at this.
Right underneath my house.
It's beautiful.
Now, where'd that creeper go?
I saw him.
There you are.
Oh, my goodness.
He died!
That's funny.
Don't explode, please.
Damn.
So athletic.
What an incredible cave!
Guys, this is a W location for a base.
What the fuck?
What is that back there?
We got the zoomer coming in!
Lovely.
There's even weird gray shit down there.
I thought this guy was T-posing for a second.
But he's not.
He's just...
I don't know what he's doing.
I'm gonna get this iron.
Wait, maybe that's what I needed.
Yo!
I think I needed the zoomer ingredient to make the back ingredient.
You know?
Maybe that was the key.
I think that may have been it.
I'm gonna limestone my way across here.
You can't stop me.
Oh, wait.
This is gonna collapse.
Is it?
Can I...
I wasn't 100% sure how that worked.
Time to cobble my way across here.
Whoa!
What a view!
Damn!
This place is amazing.
I need Potion of Night Vision!
Very far down as well.
You know what?
I'm gonna get ready.
Just in case.
You think I'll have the reaction times to actually pull it off if I fall?
Like, that would have to be next level stuff.
Actually, I'm gonna switch these two.
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
One thing I gotta be worried about is enemies spawning up top and falling down on me.
That is a massive problem.
I see you up there.
Come on.
Don't explode.
Wait!
Who was here?
It's completely robbed!
That is the saddest I've ever seen here, man.
Like, there's only one or two in there.
Give me this.
But it's fine.
I guess I can always come back later and grab some when they grow.
Is this even...
It is.
Come on.
Show me.
Show me the goods.
I'm not sure, actually.
Yeah.
That was it.
Wow.
Amethyst!
It's the name of that thing.
God damn.
This cave is bigger than you thought.
Than you would think, is what I meant to say.
How about this?
Smooth basalt.
No diamonds, though.
That's...
kind of surprising.
When there's so much surface area exposed and we can't even see a single diamond, that's...
weird.
Whoa!
Look how far down that is!
This is an...
a giga cave!
This may even be one of the...
biggest caves I've ever seen in my life.
Diamonds.
How do I get down?
Of course I know how to get down.
But how do I get up?
It's easier to get up than it is to get down.
I don't have a lot of ascension blocks.
Look at that!
Oh, but that is definitely some new stuff.
It looks weird.
More zinc?
Ooh!
There's a lot.
Jack in the background going.
Ah!
She has faces when she does that.
I think she's singing.
She always does it when I'm not in the room as well.
As if she's embarrassed, you know?
Like...
When she does that and I get up from my chair...
She stops immediately because she can hear me coming, you know?
Like she doesn't want me to know that...
She's singing.
You're gonna try and take a shot at me?
Take a shot at the king.
You best not...
Wait, what the?
Why do you look like that?
This guy had a monocle on.
I mean, that's an elevator right there.
Ayy!
Speaking of...
Just fucking do that!
Ah-ha!
Question is, do I want to do that?
Right now.
I think I do.
America!
Go!
Okay, time to evasive actions.
One at a time.
Professional gamer.
Ah-ha!
You got caught in the stream, buddy!
See ya!
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Fall.
Fall, please.
Oh, my God.
He saved himself.
Well done, buddy.
You did it.
Oh, there you are.
String.
Bam, bam.
We got to take care of that archer.
Up!
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh.
Shh.
Go fight left!
Fucking hell.
MLG gamer.
Boik.
Damn.
I'm so good.
What's up, fool?
Yup.
You're dead.
I gotta get a bow soon.
Also, let's not get lost here.
Where did I come from?
Which one is my...
Is that my ascension?
That's mine.
So let's make a little thingy here so we...
Fucking inventory opened in the middle of combat!
I couldn't move!
Dude, thank God I didn't die!
Jesus Christ!
Holy shit!
Wow.
I don't want to die down here.
I really don't.
We got greenery as well!
I need to explore that.
Fuck you and your friends.
What you've done to me today.
Fuck you.
Maybe I'll make a fucking advanced orphan crusher just to kill these assholes.
Hate these orphans!
Nobody's here.
Stalking me.
I gotta be able to find my way back.
But that should be easy enough.
I mean, as long as there's light.
And I can always just go up.
I mean, I'm pretty much just below my base right now, right?
So, should be fine.
Also, I came here for antiside.
And I found some now.
Great.
Let's grab it.
This is why I'm here.
Maybe we cordon off the area a little bit first!
I heard a man.
Oh!
I thought he was on me.
Uh, we can actually...
Yeah.
Fine!
You are my ticket to Elytra!
Down the road, at least.
I got unlucky with the drop.
It's the silly song, man!
Wee-yawn.
You know what that means.
Time to get silly...
No.
I'm not gonna get silly.
I'm gonna get serious.
Diamonds!
Doesn't get more serious than diamonds.
That's when you know...
It's business.
Okay.
I was gonna take this.
Let me take it.
I'm so worried about a creeper just...
Somehow manifesting out of thin air, you know?
48.
Man, it's really slow.
I need enchantments on this axe.
Maybe I can find a hotel somewhere.
And just really right there...
Ah, but wait.
I'm gonna need, uh...
Pick it up and take it with you.
But I don't have that.
So, this is kind of a...
Chicken and the egg situation.
Frick.
I gotta make my own bookcases.
Also level 18, which is super nice.
Hey, bro.
Actually, I welcome combat.
Because I want to level up.
Is this the...
Yeah, viridium.
Oh.
Oh, shit.
Come on.
Oh, I missed.
Oh, fuck you.
Oh, I got you.
I got you.
Oh, there we go.
You can never underestimate the children.
They will attack you.
What is that?
Oh, it's tough?
It's tough.
I probably don't even need all this.
And again.
Who knows?
Maybe Lobby's Lazuli is suddenly...
The hotshot thing you need.
With Create.
Uh-oh.
Never mind.
We're good.
Here.
Create.
Oh!
Diamonds!
And Iron.
Very good.
Ah, man.
This cave sucks for diamonds.
But it rocks for anything else.
Let's go to the green place.
This is kind of dangerous.
I'm not going to end the side my way up.
Enderman.
Yeah.
We can tussle.
Stop spinning.
Hey, what are you doing?
Is he stuck on that plant?
Hey.
Oh.
Oh, he baited me.
There we go.
And the pearl is ours.
The first and the pearl.
Let me take this.
Nah.
Okay.
Nothing exciting.
Man, this looks weird as hell.
This red stuff.
I actually don't want it.
Same with the...
Viridium.
So, the goal is to get andesite, but it's also to collect a bunch of different materials.
Such that we can potentially make it easier.
Oh, wait a second.
There was a way to produce andesite, wasn't there?
I forgot the recipe, though.
Last stream, I figured that out.
But it was something...
Was it cobblestone?
I think it may have been cobblestone.
That's also annoying to go get, you know?
So maybe...
The process is not fully figured out yet.
Oh, look at this.
Oh, nice.
How come these are not grown, man?
Let's go on here.
That's all I can get.
They're being stingy with it.
Also, I'm definitely kind of lost.
A little bit.
Like, I have my torches, but still.
I have been going off a little willy-nilly.
I guess I can collect some lava.
You know what?
Yeah.
Let's collect some lava.
Maybe that will become handy.
Nice.
That way we also stop this bullshit.
Don't have to worry about that anymore.
This cave just keeps going.
What do you got back here?
Very inhospitable terrain.
Somehow this became an iron adventure.
Okay, I think it's time we leave.
Grab a bunch of andesite on the way out.
But otherwise, just leave.
I'm also going to do this.
Excuse me?
We can stack more than 64?
That is unreal.
Are you for real?
Hold up.
Okay.
I thought I just destroyed it.
The toolbox just became S-tier.
Holy crap.
What's up, bro?
Oh, man.
He's medicining.
Stop it.
Why?
No idea where I'm going.
But you know what?
That's fine.
At some point, we're just going to go up.
And we'll be happy.
Oh, is that what I think it is?
Oh.
We got more amethyst here.
Don't want this.
There's skeleton inside of here.
Okay.
Not bad.
Man, what is going on with the amethyst?
Oh, it wasn't even grown.
Oh.
Oh, wait.
I had my shield up.
Unfair.
I'm tunnel visioning a little bit right now.
Hey, look.
We got a mine.
Brief black frame insertion.
That's actually tough.
Not what I need.
I'm taking these with me.
Is that going to unlock something new?
Let's see.
Doesn't look like it.
Oh, my God.
Where?
Don't mess with me.
Let's block that off.
Lava is bad.
Yo, and then we can...
Oh, dude.
Wait.
I wonder what the limit is on these.
I mean, yeah.
I am loving this toolbox.
Who needs pouches when you have that?
Not me.
Got a brief BFI.
Involuntary BFI.
Most of the time, BFI is voluntary.
What's going on down there?
Diamonds.
Would be nice to get a full diamond armor.
I'm actually not sure if that will make it so that I survive a creeper explosion.
Maybe I'll need the blast resistance.
Or explosion resistance.
Whatever it's called.
Yeah, I'm officially lost, but that's okay.
It is voluntary lost.
Getting lots of diamonds here.
This is the perfect spot for it, it seems.
I'm just walking around.
Hopefully nothing's going to fall on me.
Is he...
Hold on.
Someone right in here.
Or not.
Redstone's going to be the test for this toolbox.
We're probably going to accumulate a lot of that.
This toolbox feels like cheating.
Magic toolbox.
Dude, this expedition has been nuts.
If I die now, I think I will actually cry in real life.
That may be the...
The thing that makes me cry!
Wow.
Wait, where am I?
Oh, I'm here.
Oh, we unlocked a bunch of shit.
Look at this.
Wow, what the...
Oh, don't fall down there.
Oh, wait.
I came from...
I see.
We had a cave-in.
So, this is the way I wanted to go.
Would be cool if I could do this.
You know?
Boink.
I can't, though.
That's fine.
I mean...
This is just me, you know...
Squeezing the lemon, for sure.
Freaking thing is already broken as it is.
In the best way possible.
I'm out here asking for seconds, you know.
Let's see.
110.
But we already had 111.
19.
There's got to be, like, a limit to that.
Maybe it's twice the stack size or something.
And if there's no limit...
Ooh.
Diamonds.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
It's okay.
Oh, I don't have any torches.
Do I have wood?
I do.
Oh.
Wait.
I don't have any coal.
Well, that's my cue.
We're leaving.
We're getting out.
Time for ascension.
Broadcasting.
Broadcasting a podcast.
Get rid of this deep slate.
Okay, guys.
It's going to be day outside.
Because it went so well in here.
Trust me.
You know I'm right.
It is for sure day.
The sun is up.
Birds are chirping.
Wind is rustling.
The leaves and the trees.
A light breeze.
Oh, it's limestone.
It sounded weird.
What's that?
I can't see.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Go, go, go.
Oh, man.
That always makes me so nervous.
Oh, what?
We got mage fishes.
Magician fishes.
Is this where I was before?
Or is this a different one?
Oh, oh.
Hey.
Dude.
Hello.
Let's just leave, man.
I don't like this.
No torches, bad.
That's fine with me.
Let's grab some of this before we leave.
You know what?
I'm going to make some light.
I'm causing destruction.
Look at this.
Oh.
I'm destroying everything.
With my lava.
No more psst.
Okay, we got a couple psst.
Oh, we don't have room anymore.
We got to utilize this.
Andesite, go.
Just fill it up.
Now, one thing that would be tragic.
Imagine filling up the toolbox with, like, infinite items.
And you forget the toolbox.
And then you don't know where it is anymore.
Now, that would be a tragedy.
Okay.
I'm actually not going to use this andesite to make floor in my house.
Not yet.
We're going to use this andesite to craft specialized items.
So that we can potentially, down the line, get more andesite so we can make floor in the house.
Okay, I think I'm done here.
We got to leave.
I'm too worried without light.
And you're coming to me.
I think we've caused enough destruction.
So, guys, I, uh...
It's still going to be day outside.
Oh.
Why is it...
What?
Okay, let's go.
Go, go, go.
Up, up, up, up, up, up, up, up.
Yeah!
Look at this.
Okay, so we're in the Chonky Forest.
That means we got to go north.
That way.
Approximately.
Uh...
Gotta be careful, though.
I think I recognize that hill over there.
I gotta get up high.
Oh, no.
I'm actually not feeling good about this.
I gotta be honest.
Wait, maybe it's over here.
Oh, no.
Oh, fuck.
I'm lost.
No, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, this is familiar.
I mean, we can't be that far.
Okay, so there was definitely, like, a mountain range to the west of where I was.
So, it should be around...
But the problem is, these trees don't align.
Those trees back there are way too tall.
I have not been in that direction.
So...
This mountain range could actually be the mountain range in that direction down there.
It could go like that.
And then this is my house over there.
Because there was a beach nearby, remember?
That's why I grabbed the water.
You know what?
Worst case, we go over there.
We don't find it.
We go on this hill and we look around.
Yep.
That's the plan.
Ah, we should be fine.
I mean, we can't have gone that far.
No matter what.
This actually kind of looks like it.
I was over there grabbing water.
And then I...
Yeah.
And then I went like that way, remember?
With the boat.
I think we found it.
And turtles on the beach?
Yeah, it's gotta be.
Yeah, I see a torch.
Beautiful.
Heck yeah!
Navigational skills in overdrive right now.
Beautiful.
We are back home.
What a successful expedition.
And we went down this hole right here.
It's kind of funny.
Let's pluck that hole, shall we?
There we go.
Stuart, you may think that's your house, but it's not.
Don't get any ideas.
Okay.
We have lava now.
Maybe we can use that for something.
Okay, so we brought home the bacon for sure on this one.
Diamonds.
I should probably make a backup pickaxe.
Just for the future.
So I don't accidentally use all my diamonds on something stupid.
Put all the random stuff in here.
Maybe I'll just keep this for now and see what I can craft.
What can I make with the current stuff I have?
A fletching table.
Maybe that has a use.
It still doesn't have a use.
Even with the mod on.
Fuck, dude.
Actually, no, no.
It does have a use.
It's the villagers.
But it's like...
Yeah.
Okay.
Nobody wants that.
Definitely making one of these.
Let's see it.
Just dust.
Okay.
Dropper.
Is the crafter.
Let's put these things in here.
This is construction.
And redstone now.
It's both.
Wait.
I didn't bring home...
Uh, hold on a minute.
I didn't bring home any coal?
Really?
Wait a sec.
Who needs a chest when you have one of these?
Unless you can only make one toolbox.
Whoa.
Wait a sec.
Probably just make one, right?
Oh, and, uh...
Let me grab this stuff.
Uh, we don't have any coal.
Shit.
I mean, we have so much wood.
Let's burn some, uh...
Oak planks.
What?
Let's, uh...
Make the zinc.
No.
Yeah, that's good.
Really not efficient to do it this way, but...
Gotta burn...
Oh, wait, wait.
We have...
Yeah, nice.
That's something.
Oh, spyglass.
Oh.
I felt naked without it, man.
Now we are back.
Copper ingot.
Raw iron.
Keep this there.
Dude, I have so much raw iron, actually.
The most important thing, though, of course.
Andesite.
And I actually have a lot of it.
Very good.
And then we needed this stuff.
Here we go.
Andesite alloys.
Ooh, yeah.
64.
Not bad.
I even have more andesite left.
Let's make even more.
Oh, it's steward.
Level 22.
Oh, that's...
I need obsidian to make...
The enchanting table.
So I gotta...
Figure that out.
Wait, wooden bracket.
What is that?
Decorate your shafts, cogwheels, and pipes...
With a cozy and wooden bit of reinforcement.
Wait, really?
Oh.
I guess it's nice on the outside of a house.
If you wanna attach them to the...
Oh, shit.
Okay.
Wait, how did I...
Oh, yeah.
Hold on, something's wrong.
No, that's right.
We're good.
Okay, can I crush a diamond?
Diamonds are tough, right?
Amethyst shard?
It cannot!
Okay, but now that we have this amethyst shard...
We should be able to craft something cool.
Gantry shaft.
Hold on.
What else did I unlock?
Nothing super exciting.
We could make the wrench.
Three golden sheets.
All right, crushing that.
Bonk!
That's still cooking.
Nice.
We don't need the boat right now.
Or this.
Okay.
Let me see what else I can do here.
What can I make with this?
Oh, did I bring home some...
I must have brought home some bones.
After that expedition?
Wait, coal becomes black dye and gray dye?
Ink sack.
I mean, all these make sense.
This is like...
The new one, right?
What can I saw here?
I kind of want to try this.
So it's just like an automated way to process wood.
Right?
Yeah, there's nothing like super mind-blowing about that.
This one, of course, is interesting because it produces these new ones.
Island sheet, gold.
Cop...
Did I make a copper sheet yet?
I did make a copper sheet.
Did I make a gold sheet yet, though?
Oh, that's what I'm doing now.
I think we can use that somehow.
Also, we have a basin.
Wait, compacting!
And this side!
Okay, so hold on.
Flint.
Gravel.
With lava.
Who wants to make diorite?
Of all the things.
Automated packing.
Wait, this is like...
Exactly the same as me just making it with the crafting table.
Why would I...
Do that?
And decide to polish that.
I can make it polished?
Okay, well, nothing super mind-blowing there.
There's got to be something that I haven't made yet.
Like, how did I get that tank last time?
Oh!
Maybe glass!
Hello?
Glass, of course!
I gotta start thinking more basic here.
Oh, let's go to sleep first.
Let's get some sand.
Let's get some other standard materials.
Maybe some sugar cane, man.
I mean, I did collect that last time.
Maybe that did something.
Let me get that experience.
Thank you.
Oh!
Sugar!
Paper!
Okay!
Nice!
Very good.
We have a bunch of sand here.
Gotta turn it into glass.
Oh!
Fuck!
Don't...
Do it.
Oh my god!
I hate the horizontal medicine.
I...
Hold on.
How do I turn that off?
Accessibility.
No, that would be a...
Control thing.
I don't think you can.
When I press W too fast, I start sprinting and I get a little bit of medicine.
I hate it.
But it's like a brief one.
It's like...
Someone's like, here comes the airplane, but not really, you know.
How much do I have?
54.
That's probably fine.
Anything else I could collect?
Maybe fish?
Nah.
Fuck that.
I have steak.
We got the steaks.
So now we want to process this.
And we cannot blast it, right?
No.
Needs to happen here.
Stand there and...
Raw iron there.
Wonderful.
And now that we have this, it should unlock some stuff.
Yeah.
Oh, that's a lot.
What the...
Yeah!
There it is!
We got it.
And it makes so much sense too.
You know, fucking goggles.
Obviously, you need glass for that.
Sugar.
Let's make one piece of sugar.
Doesn't do anything.
Okay.
I will throw away the sugar.
It's bad for you.
Put in the rails.
Clayball.
Let's put that in here.
Okay.
So, give me the glass.
Let's see.
Engineer's goggles.
I would like to make those, but I would rather make the other one.
Copper diving helmet.
But what about the...
Let's start with this.
Copper ingot and glass.
Diving.
We can also make these now.
What is that?
Space helmet?
What the...
Wait, what are these things?
Oh, it says the table there.
The...
Whatever that is.
Let me make that.
Table.
I don't know what it's called.
Smithing table.
Iron ingot and planks.
I gots it.
Smithing.
Let's put that...
Somewhere.
Is that maybe here?
Oh, I have so much new shit in here.
Physics behavior.
Windmill sails.
I mean, I'm just copying this design here.
Maybe there's a better way to do it.
I mean...
Maybe you can make an actual old school windmill design.
You know, we're the one from Europe.
I would actually like to try and do that.
Right.
What is that?
Oh, contraption stuff?
This already looks insane to me.
So, we have a mechanical bearing and a windmill bearing.
They attach to the block in front of them.
Okay, what's it going to do, though?
Oh, it makes things rotate.
Oh, wait a minute.
I know how to use the...
The harvester now, then.
I get it.
I understand.
It's going to show me how to attach more?
Yep.
Oh, wait.
The help of superglue.
Largest structures can be moved.
Okay, but how do I make...
Oh, superglue.
It's probably like the green gloop.
Or goop.
Or even honey.
You know?
Something like that, probably.
That's like goopy and sticky.
Sticky icky.
In fact, we should collect honey from bees.
You know?
Do we have any bees?
Also, if we do that, we need a campfire.
For some reason.
Campfire.
Coal.
Oh, I don't even...
Wait, charcoal.
I can also use...
How do we make charcoal?
Charcoal.
Isn't that like burning wood?
Like, I'm talking real life right now.
Wait a sec.
Can I actually just burn wood?
Can I...
Wait, what?
Give me that.
Maybe it's the oak.
I need to put in, like, the log.
That's it!
Oh, it's right here.
Ha ha!
But why is it red?
Huh?
Wait, is it because...
Oh!
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
I get it.
Makes sense.
So, we got charcoal.
So, why did I need that charcoal?
It was to build something just now.
I sort of just forgot it.
Charcoal to make...
Oh, God.
What was I doing?
Well, we can...
Like, charcoal.
Can we use that as...
Yeah!
Wait a second.
I just discovered an infinite energy source.
Guys.
We go out there and we crank that shit on the trees.
We come home and we have infinite charcoal.
That sounds insane.
Is it?
That's the way.
Wow.
Damn.
Let's try and make a brick.
There's probably something with that.
I can see it already.
Clay.
Brick time.
Brickety-brack.
I would love a snack.
Let's see what happens now.
Here we go.
Are you ready?
I predict something big.
Ah!
Something to do with the...
With the presser.
Alrighty.
Not exciting, though.
At all.
Maybe I keep the rest of the brick.
Or the clay's...
Wooden bracket.
Put it in here.
Yeah.
What about that tank, then?
That's definitely one of the things I want to crank.
If you know what I mean.
Let's make a copper nugget.
Is that it?
Iron nugget?
Oh!
Was that a spring?
Whoa!
Wait, whoa, whoa!
Iron nugget!
What the fuck?
Hold on.
Ornate iron...
Oh, that looks kind of cool.
Oh!
I can make it with iron nuggets?
No way.
So, sync wasn't actually...
Needed...
Anyway.
Iron handle?
Attached to a block to easily grab onto it.
What?!
Hold right-click.
Grabs the handle, moving yourself around it!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold right-click while sneaking.
Grabs the handle, moving only the simulated contraption the handle is on?
Scroll, adjusts the distance, moving the handle...
Now we can make a copper handle, it looks like.
Looks like a small telephone.
Hello?
Yes?
This is dog.
No.
Let me try this.
Oh, wait!
Oh, my lord!
That is beautiful!
Wow!
That is fucking sick!
Look!
And now I'm up here.
Wow!
Immediately, I was like, wait a minute.
Can I, like, climb any mountain with this?
You know?
Like, let's say that this tree right here.
Check it out.
If I...
Can I...
Oh, I can stand on it!
If I'm fast.
Oh, no way, no way, no way.
Ah!
I love that!
Dude, the handle is one of my favorite items?
Wait, let me try the scroll.
Oh.
Oh, okay, cool.
And if I...
Right, but that's something to do with the simulated whatever, whatever.
All righty!
Love that!
That's an easy way to get to the roof here when I'm constructing.
Keep that there.
What a discovery!
I love that stuff!
Birch window.
Boom!
We don't like that.
Copper handle.
I really should make it.
Just to see if there's something else going on with that.
Wait, what?
Handle.
Huh?
Oh, you can always just turn a copper handle into an iron handle.
I'll do that.
I like this one more.
Very nice.
Okay, what else?
What else we got?
Kind of want to make this.
What else I kind of don't?
A spring!
Okay, hold on.
Boing!
Connects two blocks with a spring.
When right-clicked with a wrench, adjusts the strength of the spring.
When right-clicked with spring, increases the resting length.
And when shift-R clicked with spring, reduces the resting length.
All right.
Nuggets and two sheets.
Sounds like some kind of nasty video.
Sheets.
I don't actually have any sheets.
I should press some.
There we go.
Boink!
I love hearing the bonk in the distance.
Metal bracket.
Is that just for decorating again?
Okay, cool.
Let's make a linear chassis.
I think I did this last time, and that probably unlocked something new?
Ponder-ponder on it.
Let me actually ponder on that.
Let's really think.
Connects two identical chassis blocks next to them.
Okay, I don't get it.
I don't want to read that right now.
Later.
Secondary linear chassis.
All right.
Oh, the spring.
Right, this one is done.
Almost.
Wait, what?
Oh, that's weird.
There we go.
Spring!
Oh, wait.
What's going on here?
What is that?
That's new and exciting.
Huh?
Wait, what?
Oh.
Wait.
It's like a slinky.
Can I make it go down stairs?
Hold on.
Come on.
I mean, it is not a slinky.
It is, in fact, a spring, but...
Let me spring two things together.
What can I spring?
These two.
And right-click with a wrench.
Oh, wait.
I don't have a wrench.
I need to make it.
I was about to make one, but then...
I forgot that I was making it.
How do I get rid of this?
Oh.
You gotta hit the ends of it.
You can't hit the middle.
Very, very weird.
This is very different than anything else so far.
And...
Oh, wait.
This is what I made last time.
I remember making a whisk.
That's probably gonna do something.
Oh, don't do that.
Whisk.
Oh.
It's the...
You know, make a whipped cream machine.
I like it.
Mechanical mixer.
Andesite casing cog wheel.
Let me also clean this up a bit.
Put all this stuff in there.
Although I probably need some more stuff for that, right?
Make...
No.
Okay.
Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
Oh!
There goes the floodgates.
That's what I like to see.
Let's make it.
So this one's currently rotating.
Which is awesome.
We're gonna put a wheel on that.
Also, I'm definitely running out of normal cogs.
Planks.
Oh, I have planks.
I just need...
Uh, planks and...
Eww!
Planks...
What was it, chef?
We make eight...
CPOC.
CPG!
Cog!
There we go.
Mix them.
And then...
What did I need that for?
Wheel mount?
Oh, wait!
The springs!
Are we supposed to make suspensions with that?
That's probably what that is.
So yeah, I was making...
Oh yeah, wait.
Mechanical mixer.
That needs to be combined with...
A basin.
Yep.
Oh yeah, a wheel.
That's what I was doing here.
Big one.
Small one.
Let's have it be...
Hmm.
This looks like the place where you take a poop.
You know?
Like a little poop hole.
I don't like that.
We gotta fix it.
There.
Now it's really fast.
That's good.
And...
For this one...
Let me see.
Oh, that needs a wheel that way.
Got it.
Okay.
So really what you wanna do...
Is to...
Hmm.
I mean, I guess I could...
I don't wanna make it too complicated.
That's the thing.
Maybe I have to.
Small wheel there.
No, wait.
That's not gonna...
Do anything.
I mean, I could also use the same...
Yeah, actually.
Bucket.
Let's do that.
There.
And then...
Below that, we have this.
And that looks weird, doesn't it?
We could also use another one of those thingies.
A gear thingy.
Box and casings.
I feel like I never use a normal gearbox.
I always want the vertical.
Yeah, but then it's a little too low, isn't it?
That's the problem there.
Maybe it's fine.
Let's just try it.
That's too low.
What could I do instead?
This one's coming out here.
And I just need to translate it into...
I just needed a 90 degree angle on this.
Like...
There's gotta be an easy way...
To do that.
I mean, I guess I can do this, and then...
No, I was about to say another one on top, but that's not gonna help me.
Maybe you just don't want to do them in a line like this.
Maybe that's just a bad thing to do, you know?
I'm making life too difficult for no reason.
Let's just have it over here.
Wait, what is this?
Oh, that was a...
Was that a gearbox?
That must have been a gearbox.
Yeah.
That's rotating, good.
We have this wheel to play with, but we already have some good speed here, right?
On this bottom one.
So...
Oh, we can make it really simple.
Actually.
We could simply do this.
Shaft.
Wheel.
And then we have the other side here.
Yeah, actually, that works.
Hey!
There it is!
Ladies and gentlemen.
We did it.
Basin.
And...
Mixer.
Yeah!
That's awesome!
Hmm.
Very cool.
It's not spinning very fast, though.
Okay, let me try something here.
Can I just get rid of...
Oh, we need...
You know what?
Let's get the wrench.
I've been wanting to make this for a while.
So, three golden sheets, a stick, and a cogwheel.
Yeah!
How do I...
Oh, wait.
Stop it from spinning.
It's the shield!
Actually, I don't want the shield on anyway right now.
Yeah, the shield is bad.
It's taking up a lot of my viewport.
I need a new shield soon.
Wait, let's not do anything.
So, how do I...
Maybe adding this actually made it slower?
Somehow?
Weirdly?
I mean, who knows?
Let's see.
That is the exact same speed.
Exact same speed.
I forgot this one, too.
Maybe if I build it higher.
Oops.
Instead of having...
These.
That's spinning faster!
That is faster.
Let's make more sails.
Require sticks and anticide alloys.
Maximum sail.
Eighteen sails.
Let's try and go in the other direction here, then.
Whoops.
Stop it.
Ah, I can't reach.
I'm going crazy now.
This is the ultimate test.
Oh, I don't have enough?
Oh, that's so unsatisfying.
It needs to be symmetric.
Otherwise, I can't live with myself.
Not bad!
That looks pretty good, actually.
Okay, you ready?
Oh, we got speed!
That is way better!
Yeah!
I mean, I could also just reduce some gears.
But that's for noobs.
I like raw speed from the wind.
Yeah!
I could even add...
You know, we can keep it symmetric, actually, if we do just opposite sides here.
Nobody's gonna question that.
I don't like it.
This is produced...
By mixing?
Uh...
All right?
Okay!
That doesn't make any sense.
All
right.
Oh!
Oh, pulp!
Yeah...
Oh, actually, I could do that.
I have a lot of...
Dude, let's do it.
I got so many of these oak saplings.
And I can have water at a moment's notice.
Water!
Where are you?
No, where is my bucket?
Oh, we also gotta grab this now.
Not bad!
Get it in there.
Didn't we make some...
Charcoal here?
What happened to it?
Maybe we didn't make that much.
All right!
So, with that...
Let's see if we can't do something new.
So!
Basin!
Oh, yeah!
I wanted to do this.
I needed water.
That's why I did this.
Right.
Water time.
In.
And then...
Uh...
Wait.
Is there a better way of putting this in?
Instead of me just, you know...
Spin...
Wait.
Do I need to...
Spin!
Hmm.
I think it needs more juice.
I had the same problem last time.
Fuck.
Okay.
Uh...
We can fix it.
Actually, we can fix it pretty easy.
I think.
Famous last words.
I want to eat my gears again.
Big.
Small.
Oh, easy fix!
Wait.
No.
Here.
And then.
And then...
Wait.
No.
Not really.
Eww.
Hmm.
Actually, yes.
Yes.
Almost.
Wait.
If I do it...
I do it.
How do I...
Oh, no.
Not this one.
Small one.
No.
That's the wrong spot for it.
I mean, we could just be mega...
Mega shitty.
That's ugly, though.
Like...
Nuh-uh.
I'm not doing that.
That's disgusting looking.
Gotta be a more elegant way.
Give me that.
Wait.
If I put...
Oh, my God!
I can hit it from the side!
Alright.
In that case...
Well, well, well, well, well.
We're gonna rot it.
We're gonna slot it.
It's too small.
Right.
That makes sense, actually.
Ah, shh.
I mean, we could just do this...
Up.
Boom.
That looks better!
It does.
Wait a sec.
Yeah, it looks...
It looks okay.
In fact, I like it.
I like the way that looks.
We can probably even make it look sexy.
Check this out.
Fuck yeah, dude.
That is...
Oh!
Hello!
I love it!
That right there is sexy.
Watch this work.
Pulp time!
Pulp me!
What is wrong?
Why won't you pulp?
Why are you pulp?
Okay, well...
Hmm.
Oh!
I see the problem!
We're...
Oh!
We're slowing down!
Fuck me, dude.
Terrible.
You know what?
I have an idea.
We're going underground, baby.
We're utilizing...
We're utilizing vertical space.
Watch this.
It's not working?
Does that not connect?
Hold on.
Is it because of this casing?
Boom.
And...
Yep!
That's great!
And now...
Here it comes.
Oh, it's actually perfect!
Maybe.
Oh, it is!
It is!
It's beautiful!
Watch.
Here it comes.
We put the rod on.
Small one?
We need one more rod.
Rod me.
Boom!
And?
Yep!
That's a spin right there!
Bracket that shit!
Cover it up!
I'm not even going to check first!
I know it's going to work!
Cover that up there, I guess.
Wait, can I put a bracket on a big wheel?
How's that going to look?
Alright, that's expected, I guess.
Haha!
Uh...
That's fine.
Leave it.
Yep.
And that one.
Fill that up.
Can I?
A!
A little janky, but...
How does that even work?
Okay, nobody sees it.
That's good!
We made it work, baby!
I hope.
Please work now.
Pull!
Mixing it up, baby!
And now we can make that!
What was that?
What?
Am I blind?
Hold on.
Maybe it's the...
The other side?
Ah!
It's the other side!
Oh!
We're going to press that bastard!
Watch the bunk!
Wait a second!
Can I maybe use this increased power we currently have?
To do amazing things.
Yes, we can!
Dude, are you ready?
We're going to transfer?
Hold on.
Gearboxes.
I need more.
One more vertical gearbox, please.
That takes some wheels.
Okay.
Gear.
Wait, no!
Gearbox!
Actually.
Wait, that made a new item?
Wait, can I turn a normal gearbox into a vertical?
I guess that's what that means.
Wait.
Hold on.
Something's wrong.
Ah!
Okay.
Oh, shit.
There we go.
I see what happened.
Alright, so now...
Uh, now we gotta...
Actually, no, wait.
We need...
Yeah, this one here.
And this one here.
Oh, wait.
Shit, no.
No, wait.
It don't work like that.
Never mind.
I'm drunk.
I'm not drunk, but it feels like I am.
I fucked up.
It's fine.
That belongs there.
Vertical.
He didn't see nothing.
Bracket that.
Oh, yes.
Okay!
I'm happy.
Boom!
Bonk it!
Ugh.
Part and parcel.
Oh, cardboard!
Right.
Let me see that.
Cardboard helmet.
And...
Cardboard.
Block of cardboard.
You know what?
Let's make a bunch of pulp.
Oh, I like that sound.
That's beautiful.
Ha-ha!
Oh, it's done already?!
Oh, wait.
Oh, shit.
It needs continuous source of water.
That's why we have pipes!
Oh, my God.
But how does that work?
Wait.
Pipe.
Don't we need, like, a sucker?
Something that goes...
On the water and then just, you know?
Into it.
Wait.
Uh...
Covering it.
Pipe.
Oh, we need the little...
Oh.
Oh!
That's what they are for!
Fluid?
Why are they different?
Oh, you can do it in any way?
So I can make a vertical pipe?
Or a...
Okay.
Hmm.
Oh!
Okay!
Okay, we got some stuff!
We got some stuff here!
Mechanical!
That's the word I was looking for.
Pump!
Not a sucker.
I thought it said sucker.
Like, I don't know what I'm thinking right now.
Synapses are firing.
Uh...
Let me...
I need to...
Yes!
Show me.
Dude, that looks insane!
Go in the flow of their attached pipe networks.
Okay.
Oh, I see.
So...
Alright, alright, alright.
Cool.
Show me more.
Oh, you spin it!
Of course!
Yes!
Oh, then the water goes!
That's amazing.
That is fucking great.
What a genius idea for a mod.
It's so well thought through.
The network behind is now pulling fluids.
Yes!
Yep.
Okay.
Right.
And you can reverse direction, I guess, for the opposite way.
The pop's direction is unaffected by the input rotation.
Never mind!
Oh, there's a little arrow on it.
That's probably what that means.
Instead, a wrench can be used to reverse the direction.
Got it!
Oh, that means you don't have to reassemble this whole thing every time.
I see.
It makes sense!
It makes sense.
Wow!
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
That sounds so much fun.
Let's try that.
But how do we connect it to this?
Pop!
Pipes!
More pipes.
Pipe me up.
Before I go, go.
I'm gonna pipe into the water.
Isn't that just gonna suck up dirt right now?
Let's see.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna crank that shit!
We're cranking it manually.
Also, my inventory is suddenly turning into...
Well, pulp.
Let's prevent that.
Keep this one.
Dut, dut, dut.
And the side.
Dirt.
Yep.
All this goes in.
Honestly, these two can also stay in here right now.
Yep.
And then...
Glass.
Sticks.
Okay.
Oh, shh.
Oh, fuck.
Wait a minute.
I just realized something.
How am I gonna do that with this?
Does that even work?
That don't even work!
What am I smoking?
And now we...
Now we crank it.
Yeah!
Am I sucking up water?
Maybe it's going the wrong way.
Let me try the wrench.
Oh, wait.
The arrow's pointing this way.
Okay, okay.
Maybe I do need to...
Make a little hole there.
Suck it up!
Come on!
Maybe you need more speed, you know?
Because fighting forces here, you know?
Hmm.
Maybe we need a little more space like that.
Let me try a pipe here then.
I probably need to connect it to something.
Yeah, let me try and connect it to...
So we had another thing we could make, right?
Some kind of, uh...
Container thingy.
Wait!
Fluid valve!
Okay, we gotta make that.
Okay, let's ponder on it.
Fine.
I'll do it.
Valve pipes help control fluids propagating through pipe networks.
Okay.
Their shaft input controls whether fluid is currently allowed through.
Okay, so it's a gate.
Given rotational force in the opening direction, the valve will open up.
That is so funny.
It is actually a valve.
It could be closed again by reversing the input.
Dude.
Fucking W.
Let me see.
Uh, there was something else I could make though.
And...
Wait, where is it?
It's something like a window type deal.
This one.
Fluid tank.
We need barrel.
And for that we need wood.
Uh, slabs.
Yeah.
Okay.
And two copper sheets.
Oh, I don't have that.
Oh my god.
We gotta go bonk.
Bonk that shit.
Ha ha ha.
Oh.
Oh man.
It's great.
This is great.
It makes sense too.
You like fucking sheets.
You know?
Sheets here on the sides.
Yes.
Gimme.
Rest goes on.
Now we have this.
Tank.
We should ponder on that.
What the hell is that up there?
Fluid tanks can be used to store large amounts.
amounts of fluid.
Wait.
Are you saying we can store more fluid than...
Oh.
Okay.
Type networks can push and pull fluids from any side.
But surely I'll be able to pull from the ocean.
Dude, I can totally pollute the ocean!
The contained fluid can be measured by a comparator.
Of course it can.
However, in survival mode, fluids cannot be added or taken manually.
Oh.
Why would I do that?
You can use basins, item drains, and spouts to drain our...
Okay, this is getting too much for me.
I don't even understand what's happening right now.
Fluid tanks can be combined to increase the total...
Oh, yeah.
Right.
Okay.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
Just like the item vault.
Their base square can be up to three blocks wide.
And let me guess.
Three times the length of the diameter.
Jesus.
This is fucking sick.
Tell me this works.
Come on.
Maybe I am too slow here.
Hold on.
Let me get some power going.
I'm going to do something quick and dirty.
Quick and dirty.
We need more wheels.
Shafts.
Woods.
Wah!
What am I doing?
Dirt.
Okay, now speed.
What's the fastest we have?
We have speed over here, but that's...
Yeah.
Alright.
Fine.
I'll take it from there.
I'll take it.
Okay.
Now we shaft it.
Whatever.
Oh, wait.
It's the other way.
I know it's not pretty.
It's not supposed to be.
There's a better way to do this.
Okay, fuck it.
Let's not take from there.
Let's take from here.
That means...
Like that.
Oh, wait, wait.
Actually, it's fine.
It's perfect.
Gearbox.
Vertical gearbox.
No.
Actually, horizontal gearbox.
Other one.
There it is.
Huh?
No, no.
Not that.
Boom.
Is it fast?
Enough?
Suck up that water.
It's like an animation.
Hold on.
Are you sucking?
Maybe it can only transport between two fluid containers.
No way, right?
Or maybe you need the valve.
And a slight alloy and sheets.
Okay, we unlock a bunch of new stuff here.
Oh, wait.
Okay, I need to see this again.
Give me this.
Okay, but sure.
Yeah.
It can be big.
I get it.
What about the freaking...
Cover casing can be used to decorate.
Come in, this one.
Yes.
Yeah, yeah.
Yep.
Like, this is not even spinning that fast.
Wait, does it need redstone?
Right.
Regardless of speed, mechanical pumps affect pipes connected up to 16 blocks away.
Okay.
Oh, wait.
We can...
We can pull lava?
Ah!
Speeding up the input rotation changes the speed of flow...
I mean, that makes sense.
Yeah.
And the speed at which fluids are transferred.
Yeah, I get it.
But why won't it suck it up from the ocean or from a little pool?
Pumps can combine their throughputs within shared pipe networks.
Oh, sick.
All right.
Ensure that all of them are facing in the same direction.
Right.
Makes sense.
Oh, that's actually so cool.
They all spin each other.
Let me try not to have this...
Maybe it needs to come in from an angle, like...
Like, check it.
We go like this.
Down.
And then right.
Maybe now.
I'm also gonna take my bucket.
Make sure this is completely filled.
There we go.
Pump.
Pump, pump, pump.
Oh!
There it is!
It needed to come in at an angle!
All right!
Oh!
Right.
Oh, shit.
Okay.
Stop.
But wait, do we have infinite water from here?
Oh, that produces a little...
Oh.
Oh, that's interesting.
Okay, so now to figure out how to connect this to this thing.
I wonder if it's as simple as just...
Boink!
Right into it.
Let's check it out.
Uh...
Here?
Ahaha!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
No way.
Oh, wait.
This needs to be over here.
It auto-connected.
That has to mean...
That it just works.
Come on!
Let's do it, man!
In!
I believe.
Come on.
Water.
Oh, the pipe is coming out.
Look!
Wait, what?
I may have connected this wrong.
It also does look a little weird that it's clipping through, you know?
Water should be...
Sucked in right now.
Whoa!
Jesus!
Okay, it's...
Give me this back.
There's...
Let me figure out how to connect these properly.
Maybe what we need is...
I'm just gonna guess a little bit here.
Wait, let me see if that actually fills up.
Let's see.
That should just fill up right now.
Get ready with the bucket.
In case...
Oh, let me actually empty this.
Also, I'm gonna have to...
Wait, is this...
It is spinning the right way.
Why is that not filling up?
I need food.
Wait, it's at 16, right?
Or something?
One, two, three, four...
Five, six, seven, eight, nine...
Oh my god, dude!
I'm so jumpy right now!
Fuck off!
I'm thinking!
Let me go to bed.
I can't with this fucking thunder and spiders attacking me while I'm trying to think about pipe networks!
Okay, check it out.
Maybe it needs to come in directly and not at an angle, you know?
So maybe if we do this...
Wait.
Oops.
Wait, is it gonna...
Is water even gonna come out here?
Let's see.
Let's see!
Come on, then!
Because if it's not...
Then obviously we need more pumps.
Or more speed.
No, it will...
It said at any speed it will pump.
Right?
It said it would pump at any speed.
It's just about range.
You know what?
Let's...
We can make this simpler.
I have an idea.
I don't know why I didn't think of this before.
Check it out.
This is actually fucking genius what I'm about to propose.
We make a hole.
Right there!
You see that?
See that hole?
We fill it with water.
Actually, we need at least two holes.
Uh...
Three holes.
And then we need this.
This is so stupidly simple.
It's gonna work.
You'll see.
Pump.
Like, it doesn't get any closer than this.
I wonder if it'll auto-adjust.
No.
Okay.
It's not auto-angle.
Does this auto-angle?
Yes, it does!
Okay.
Oh, wait.
Uh...
Basin.
There we go.
Okay.
Now we need a wheel on this sucker.
Good thing we have a wheel right there.
Can we use it?
Oh, this is gonna be annoying.
Uh...
Oh, actually.
Yes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Oh, wait.
The other way.
Shit!
Oh, fuck.
Uh...
You know, I-I-we cranked that shit!
We cranked it.
I don't give a shit.
Crank time.
Cranking...
Boom.
Ready?
Here we go.
Not that way, silly.
Here we go!
Come on, water!
Pump it in!
Pump, pump, pump, pump!
Come on!
Wait, is it wrong?
Is it right?
Oh!
Uh-huh!
There we go.
Pump it!
Come on!
Yes!
It's working!
So it was about distance.
Let me see if it actually works like this now.
I just want to test.
Give me the water.
Come on.
No.
Okay, okay.
Let me remove this then.
No, it doesn't work like that.
Okay.
Fine.
Kind of sad that it doesn't work that way with just down because it feels more natural to just do down, you know?
Like, suck it up!
Now we got to give it some juice, man.
You know what?
Let's think backwards.
This is what geniuses do.
You put this in first!
The other way.
Not that way.
Not- Not- Jesus.
Wheel me!
There we go.
And now we figure out the rest from here.
And see, I already see the solution!
Wait.
Ah!
I see it, I see it.
Vertical gearbox.
It is obvious.
Vert.
Where's my gear- Didn't I have an extra one somewhere?
Is that the one?
Oh, give me that, give me that.
It's not even a vertical one!
Vert.
But this one.
We're gonna put it in!
And it's gonna feel good.
It's not spinning because it's not connected.
Watch.
Boom!
Yeah, it's simple!
It works!
Pulp!
Come on!
What's wrong?
Is it?
No!
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
That's it!
Come on!
That's crazy!
It's gonna be continuously filled!
Watch!
Here it comes!
Come on!
You need more juice.
I got oak for you!
Come on!
Pulp me!
Okay, wait.
I think it's full.
Let's go!
Why is it not- What's wrong with it?
Oh!
Oh, it's- Oh!
Oh, you can't-
I see- Wait, wait, wait.
Really?
Okay.
So you can't just do that.
I see how it is.
So you can't just- They're not gonna let you get infinite water.
And now it's spinning, look!
But it's gonna suck the water out!
But what if I put it- Wait, if I put it in the ocean, is it gonna empty the ocean?
No, but it's not sucking the rest out.
Dude, I'm gonna empty the ocean.
We gotta test something.
Uh...
Oh, man.
I don't wanna- I guess I could- I could crank it.
I'm gonna crank it.
That's all I need.
Give me this.
We're going to the ocean, baby.
You're gonna see some serious shit.
Actually, we're gonna bring- Yeah, good.
We have it all.
It's actually gonna suck up the ocean.
Uh, pipe.
And it needs to go down and- There.
Actually, we don't need this here.
There we go.
The right way.
And boom!
Ah, wait, that- That's, uh...
Let me do this instead.
Oh, I broke my- Okay.
You ready?
Here we go.
It's cranking time.
Crank that shit!
Watch.
Maybe if it allows- If we can go further with it?
I mean, I'm kind of an expert on water physics in Minecraft at this point.
Trust me.
I have mastered the flow.
I'm gonna explain to you what happens, or how this works, in, like, exactly 37 seconds, okay?
I'll show you what I mean.
Okay, here's what happens.
I understand everything.
Uh, the full thesis is coming right now.
So, if- Uh, it's taking the block of water.
That's what's happening.
It's taking the block.
So let's say I want to take the water from here.
It's actually gonna empty it here.
And bring it to there.
It's a transportation of a block of water.
I get it.
Hold on.
Thesis is incomplete, but it is complete now.
I know what to do now.
It is just like a water bucket.
So, let me ask you something.
Where should you take the water from with a water bucket?
If you want infinite water.
Is it A?
Is it B?
Or is it C?
Yes, it's B!
Right?
So we put it in the center.
Sure.
Actually, we can move it.
There.
Watch this now.
I need a...
Wait.
I just need a bit more.
This will work.
There we go.
Boom.
And...
Pipe time.
Spin it.
Water level is steady.
It's going up.
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
There it is.
And nothing is being sucked, because we are taken from the center.
It's the same logic, just with the...
With the bucket.
And now it's this.
Oh, my God.
We're making so much pulp.
18 pulp.
Let's smash that pulp.
Oh, wait.
It's not...
Oh, it needs a certain amount of pulp before it can...
I see.
Okay.
Dude, that is something I love.
Can we mix and match?
Hold on.
One more.
We can.
Yo.
Oh.
And then we bring this automatically onto that.
Somehow.
That's the next step.
Dude.
I see it now.
I see the vision.
I see...
I see clearly.
You know?
I was blind, but now I see.
Oh, that's got...
This is going to be insanely funny, I think.
I can't wait to do that.
I see the whole thing in front of me.
I see every single part of this mod coming together right now.
Why can't I grab it?
Grab it!
Huh?
Why doesn't this work anymore?
Wait, what?
Ah!
You can't have anything in your hands.
Oh, fuck!
Come on!
Ah!
There we go.
Oof!
Holy shit, man.
And all of this from the windmill!
Great.
Give me that.
Actually, we're not done.
We have cardboard now.
We can make things out of cardboard.
Let's make a block of it!
Oh, right.
We can...
What?
What's that?
That's new!
There's something new there.
Packager?
Sending packages?
Oh, dude.
This is actually fucking thick.
Mmm!
Delicious.
Are you done?
Bonking?
Good.
Thank you.
Oh.
Dude, imagine if you can put your thing on here and make it sharper by ping, ping, ping, ping, you know?
Like a smith.
That'd be kind of cool.
In here.
Uh, this goes here.
Copper valve handle.
I guess cardboard, technically, belongs there.
Let me just prepare this properly.
And the side alloy in here.
Good sorting.
Oh, put that in there.
Hand crank.
I think that should stay with...
The saw.
Keep things a little consistent.
I need to make another shovel.
We have diamonds, so we're making a diamond shovel.
Wait, no.
Yep, that's good.
Blew it well.
Okay.
That's it for now.
There we go.
What do you say to that?
Isn't that amazing?
I think it's...
Unbelievably...
Entertaining.
I absolutely love the vision of the mod.
I totally see it all now.
I see it clearly.
I see what they're trying to do.
It just clicked for me there at the end.
Beautiful mod.
Guys, you have to make the wheel spin intact.
Or in sync with the music.
Are you gonna try to do it together?
Or let one guy...
I'm just kidding.
That's pretty much impossible for you guys to do.
I don't think that's something you could ever achieve, actually.
Without coordinating, somehow.
I didn't get the meter set up yet.
The one with the power gauge.
I'll think about it.
This was such a fun session.
Love the stream.
I missed the beginning.
Why did you start over?
I started over because...
The first one was a bit of a disaster from start to finish.
And I had bad...
I had a bad vibe coming from...
What I did in the first episode.
That's it.
And now that I created this more native mod...
I thought it was also a good opportunity to start over.
Just to not have any bugs, you know?
With the progression.
Like 50-50 on those reasons.
It's way more easy to understand the progression now...
With the way I've set things up.
And not having this weird JEI panel.
That is just, you know, confusing as hell.
This is way more intuitive for me.
As someone who just knows Minecraft vanilla.
Did I promise a Jackie cam?
I don't know if I did.
I mean, I said maybe.
The thing is, I'm moving soon.
So maybe in the new place, I'll set up something more permanent.
I'm also gonna be in a bigger room where I'm streaming.
So I could actually have a little cat bed there.
There's physically room for it.
And then I could easily set a webcam up to look at her.
Maybe during breaks, you know?
I don't want a cat cam during gameplay.
But during breaks?
Hell yeah.
Yo!
We could make it some...
Check it out.
You guys spin the wheels to reach a certain threshold.
Which then dispenses a little snack for Jackie.
That...
I could totally code that.
No problem.
That could be so fun.
Imagine that.
That is the best idea ever.
Yo!
We should do that.
We're gonna do that.
100%.
Jackie's gonna get fat.
No, no.
We're gonna have like an internal cooldown on it or something.
Just so you can't spam the snack meter, you know?
How you coded this?
Let's just say I choreographed...
This mod.
To take form.
IQ too high?
I don't know about that.
Probably not.
But it is fun.
What's this music from?
It is from one of the best games ever made.
Called Blueprints.
It is so good.
So how do you like it so far?
I love it.
I think this season is gonna be so much fun.
No Yumu blueprints.
I heard out of wild.
What?
How did you hear that?
Blueprints is so good, but I'm too stupid for that?
No.
Dude, if you watch my gameplay, I'm gonna look stupid too.
It's just...
It's a puzzle game.
It's designed to challenge you, right?
To be challenging.
To be a puzzle.
It's like the most normal thing.
To be stuck on a puzzle in a game that's designed to make you be stuck on puzzles.
You know?
You really created today?
I did.
Man, I did.
I feel so much better about this stream than the last one.
Be honest.
Did AI code the mod?
What did I just say?
Of course.
In this day and age, obviously, Fable slash Opus is 10,000 times better at me than coding nowadays.
And it's gonna get better and better by the week.
I think I spent around 80 hours or so coding this shit.
Choreographing it.
Telling it what to do.
If you think about it, it's kind of fucked up, right?
It's a...
It's a human...
Basically telling a bunch of numbers to create a bunch of other numbers.
So that the human can interact with that set of numbers.
And that set of numbers brings the human joy.
What a world we live in.
Non-programmers judge AI coding so much, but it's inevitable.
Dude, any serious programmer is using AI for sure to some degree nowadays.
It is just too good to ignore.
Fucking Linus Torvalds.
The inventor of Linux is using it.
Even he can't disagree with the fact that it's useful.
You really mined and crafted today.
And created.
Don't forget that.
It was amazing to watch.
I'm glad you enjoyed it, man.
Thank you.
When is the next stream?
Next time I'm gonna play Binding of Isaac.
Because I feel like playing that.
I need to have a couple of runs on that.
But the next stream after that, we're gonna do Minecraft again.
Are we finally getting 30 bushels and spinning ballerinas?
Now that we have the capability?
Yes!
Definitely.
Yeah, Meep's Kitten.
I think it's because most people use free AI.
You know, you go on chatgpt.com.
And honestly, those suck.
Like, if you haven't tried a Frontier model like Fable or something right now, you don't even understand what the level is at.
Like, you have no clue.
It is not even the same world.
You plan on streaming The Sims again?
Yes, but maybe a little less.
Because now I'm kind of getting consumed by Minecraft again.
If I'm being totally honest.
Especially right now, I'm feeling it, you know?
Like, after that session just now?
Man.
I'm getting a little addicted.
Once again.
The ecological impact of AI is really bad, though.
So is many other things.
You ever bought shoes or clothes?
Made by children.
That's not cool either.
I mean, the world is what it is.
You ever eat meat?
Yeah.
I mean, the amount of water it takes to just raise a cow up and slaughter it?
It's like insanity.
Not to mention the whole slaughtering a cow thing.
I mean, I still eat meat, but, you know.
I do realize it's kind of fucked up.
The way we treat animals.
Did you play Deltarune Chapter 5 yet?
No, I haven't played any Deltarune at all.
I'm waiting for the entire game to be finished.
And then I'll play it.
You know?
It's like watching a TV show.
I would rather have all the seasons, and then I can binge it.
Because I know if I don't, I'm gonna watch the first seasons and then forget about it and not care about the fifth season when it comes out, you know?
It's just better that way.
Lava plus water.
You will wait five years?
For what?
Oh, for the game?
Yeah, yeah.
I guess it's gonna take a while.
That's fine, though.
I'm a patient gamer.
I don't mind waiting.
There is a way...
Oh, hold on.
I need to read this.
There is a way for you to not double-click W for sprint.
Just put it on toggle, then set a different keybind for it.
I personally use...
Oh, wait.
Wait.
I...
Okay.
I'm gonna check that out.
That doesn't sound like it makes...
I don't know if I want to use R.
Why do you not use control for sprinting?
Because I've played games.
Minecraft is like the only game in the universe who does sprint on control as default.
Minecraft is in the wrong here.
Every other game is in the right.
Excuse me.
Bam.
Like, what other game on earth has control as sprint?
It's like illegal.
Who came up with that?
It's too ingrained in my brain to shift it.
I could change it, of course.
But it's gonna be painful to watch.
I'm gonna fall to my death a million times and that's just not worth it.
Q for sprint is POG.
You know why it's not POG?
Because it takes your finger off A.
And you want to keep all your fingers on WASD at all times.
You want to use your pinky for sprint.
Shift for sprint and control for crouch.
Yeah.
That works.
Or even in some games, C for crouch is also something I'm happy with.
I'm like 50-50 on control or C for crouch.
Both are pretty good.
Who says you can't access Q with your pinky?
I mean, I'm trying that right now.
That is...
Oh, wow.
Shoo, that's bad.
But if you can do that consistently, then...
I applaud you.
Good job.
Do you read books?
Actually, not that much anymore.
I used to.
Nowadays, I play more video games and watch TV shows.
But I do want to read some books again.
I just need a good book, I guess.
Something that gets me excited.
How about left thumb for left shift?
Left thumb for left...
What type of books do you like?
Um...
It's hard to explain.
No, it's not hard to explain.
I like good books.
Some books are just...
like, impossible to put down once you start them, you know?
Page turners.
Those are the only ones I can read.
If it's a book that is not a page turner, I will...
not read at all.
And it could be anything.
But I guess I like science fiction.
What's the most recent show I finished?
That's a good question.
I don't remember.
Oh yeah, I do remember.
It's called Happy Valley.
A British show.
It was incredible.
Highly recommended.
Happy Valley.
It's like a crime cop TV show.
It's super good.
And also British TV shows that are really good.
In the Line of...
No.
Line of Duty, it's called.
Yeah, Line of Duty is incredible.
I highly recommend that one.
One of the best TV shows, man.
The English know how to make shows.
I'll give them that.
Can you try to speak Danish?
What do you want to say?
I don't think any one of you is going to understand, though.
Maybe one...
Two percent of you?
Or perhaps from Denmark?
I don't speak Danish all the time.
Dude.
Sounds like simlish?
Maybe?
I don't know how it sounds like.
I mean, to me it sounds normal.
Okay, guys.
I feel like this music is kind of fitting for the wheels.
Maybe next time I'll make it so that every time you spin the wheel, the timer for the countdown goes down faster.
So if you want the stream to start faster, you have to spam.
And I start the countdown at an hour.
There's so many fun ideas for this shit.
Okay, I'm out of here.
Guys, thank you so much for watching.
This was a blast, dude.
I finally see it.
Create, baby.
It's fun.
I'll see you around.
Bye-bye.